<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Django on Martin Chorley</title>
    <link>https://martinjc.com/tags/django/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Django on Martin Chorley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 09:20:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://martinjc.com/tags/django/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Django &#43; Last.FM Authentication</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2012/02/27/django-last.fm-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 09:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2012/02/27/django-last.fm-authentication/</guid>
      <description>Following a conversation with Jon last week, I&amp;rsquo;ve been having thoughts about playing around with Last.FM data again, having not looked at that API for a couple of years. We had discussed the possibility of using the Last.FM web services as part of a project at a hackathon that some of the undergraduates are running in a couple of weeks time, and since I&amp;rsquo;ve moved from primarily developing using Java to mainly using Python since I last did anything with Last.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BoxUK &#34;For the Social Good&#34; Hackday</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/11/22/boxuk-for-the-social-good-hackday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 10:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/11/22/boxuk-for-the-social-good-hackday/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I attended the &amp;ldquo;For the Social Good&amp;rdquo; hackday, organised by BoxUK and held at the Students Union at Cardiff University. As you may have gathered from the title, it was a hackday themed around creating apps that had some benefit to society. The event ran from 10am to 10pm, so it was a fairly short hack event compared to some, which had a big influence on what could be done during the time available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foursquare Hackathon Post Mortem</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/11/22/foursquare-hackathon-post-mortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 10:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/11/22/foursquare-hackathon-post-mortem/</guid>
      <description>Note: I wrote this post just after the hackathon, but then forgot to actually publish it! 
There&amp;rsquo;s a fair amount I learnt from taking part in and helping to organise the foursquare hackathon here at the university that probably deserves its own post. I&amp;rsquo;ll split it into two parts, the taking part and the organisation.
Organising a hack event There were a couple of things I learnt from helping to organise the event that perhaps weren&amp;rsquo;t clear to begin with:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foursquare Hackathon Cardiff - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/09/17/foursquare-hackathon-cardiff-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 19:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/09/17/foursquare-hackathon-cardiff-day-1/</guid>
      <description>I was fully intending to try and live-blog the progress of the foursquare hackathon today, even going as far as to install a live blog plugin, but things have been going very quickly and we&amp;rsquo;ve been hitting the coding hard so I just haven&amp;rsquo;t had time!
We&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get a decent crowd in, a roughly 50:50 split of people we already knew from the School and other people from elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django &#43; Foursquare &#43; OAuth = webapp?</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/09/08/django-foursquare-oauth-webapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 17:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/09/08/django-foursquare-oauth-webapp/</guid>
      <description>Moving on from my fun with getting django + twitter + oauth to play nicely, it&amp;rsquo;s now time to start writing a web app that uses foursquare as the authentication/login method. As part of this, I need a basic django framework for doing authentication with foursquare. This may be useful to someone else at some point (including me when I forget in three months time how I did things), so I&amp;rsquo;ve written up the details and added the code to github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django &#43; Tweepy &#43; OAuth</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/04/04/django-tweepy-oauth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 18:27:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/04/04/django-tweepy-oauth/</guid>
      <description>There is a lot of information out there that talks about putting Django and Tweepy together to make a Twitter web app. I read a lot of it recently, and although a lot of it is helpful some of it can be quite complicated or out of date.
To make things simple, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d create an example Django project that just contains the basics needed to get up and running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Wordle</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/04/04/twitter-wordle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 13:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/04/04/twitter-wordle/</guid>
      <description>Next week we have the project partners coming over to Cardiff for a workshop. Stu and myself were discussing that we should have some way to display information throughout the day, something that makes it easy to pick out the main themes of talks etc. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the Wordle as a way of displaying text, so we thought it would be nice if we could have a dynamic Wordle displayed that people could add to throughout the workshop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fun with django...</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/03/28/fun-with-django.../</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 21:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/03/28/fun-with-django.../</guid>
      <description>One of the latest ideas we are working on for the new project is looking at how providing different amounts of information affects our perception of content. Even in pure implementation terms this is interestingly unlike any of the work I&amp;rsquo;ve done in the last few years, most of which was simulation based. &amp;ldquo;Code a simulation, run the simulation, analyse the results&amp;rdquo; has been a pattern of work since the beginning of my PhD and beyond.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>