<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>martin chorley</title>
    <description>I am Dr Martin Chorley, a lecturer at the School of Computer Science &amp; Informatics, Cardiff University, programme leader for the MSc in Computational and Data Journalism.
</description>
    <link>https://martinjc.com//</link>
    <atom:link href="https://martinjc.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 16:21:06 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 16:21:06 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes - 29th May 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;monday-29th-may&quot;&gt;Monday 29th May&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BANK HOLIDAY, innit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;tuesday-30th-may&quot;&gt;Tuesday 30th May&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OH GOD, NOW I’VE GOT A DAY LESS TO DO EVERYTHING!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finished my visualisation coursework marking today. Generally really good quality across the board, and a really enjoyable set of work to mark. As time goes on, I’m liking this visualisation course more and more. It’s fun to teach as it’s an interesting and quite subjective field, which is not usual in a ‘normal’ Computer Science course. There’s lots of scope for discussion and argument and plenty of chances for students to really get stuck into some data analysis and communication and really show off their skills. I get the feeling the mark distribution skewed a little higher than last year, but I haven’t checked that yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also met with the last student who has expressed an interest in our CUROP project for this summer, so we’ll be able to make a decision on that soon and get that project rolling. I also met with another of our CompDJ students about their dissertation project - they’re looking to build a bot that will write articles automatically about particular topics. A very ambitious project, but one that looks to be really interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other major task on Tuesday was a Skype call with the rest of the organising committee of DataJConf to finalise the accepted talks and sort out the schedule. We had a really great set of submissions, with a good mix from industry and academia. Our programme committee did a great job of reviewing them, so it was a fairly simple task to conduct a quick meta-review of the papers, decide where our cut-off point is and then take the top 8 papers forward to the conference. Sadly the fact that we’re only one-day main track this year meant we had to lose some very good submissions, but I’m hopeful those authors will still come along and pitch their discussion topics for the Unconference on the day after DataJConf (and we invited them to in their notification emails). The &lt;a href=&quot;http://datajconf.com/#schedule&quot;&gt;schedule is now online&lt;/a&gt;, and it looks like it’s going to be a really good day. Tickets are selling, and the attendee numbers are ticking up. We were supposed to make a decision this week on which room to go for, the big room or the bigger room, but we put that off to see how numbers look in a weeks time. It’s a bit of a gamble as there’s always a chance that if we need to switch from the room we already have booked the other room will be unavailable by the time we make our minds up, but who doesn’t like a bit of risk in their conference planning?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;wednesday-31st-may&quot;&gt;Wednesday 31st May&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A day in which very little was accomplished towards my own goals, but which had to be done. Most of the morning was taken up with a meeting with my counterpart in undergraduate operations, the school manager, and various faces from college about our generally low survey response rates in the School, and how we might do better at communicating with students to foster a culture that encourages these response rates to improve. One of the key points we came up with was that while we’re very good at listening to students as a school, and then acting upon their feedback, we’re pretty rubbish at communicating those actions and changes back to the students. The outcome of this discussion was a need to empower the operations teams for postgrads and undergrads to do more with the various surveys and module feedback questionnaires, to bring actions and recommendations to the teaching and learning quality committee and boards of studies, and to work with the comms team to make sure students know that what they tell us is listened to and acted upon, and is therefore quite important. Essentially it’s about a culture change within the school, and we all know how easy that is, right…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also had some interesting discussions with my Head of School today about a number of projects I’ve got going on at the moment. I already &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinjc.com/2017/05/22/weeknotes-220517/&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; about trying to coordinate the large number of new programme / programme change approvals that we have happening within the school, but we also discussed a couple of other projects. One, looking at end-of-module feedback has been going on for a while but is close to being ready for launch. The other was around module-review, and how I want to improve that process by moving to a git based approach, which will allow better oversight and review of module changes and data collection. I’ll talk more about that as the project develops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At lunchtime we had our first official meeting with Stuart, our third-year student who is working with us for the summer on our Education Innovation chatbot project. He seems to have really hit the ground running and is getting stuck in to building code and designing solutions. Really great to see, and it looks highly likely that we’re going to have something working to test with students in the Autumn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The afternoon was taken up with an Academic Approval Event in the School of Modern Languages. I was on the panel as the internal member from outside the college. It’s the second approval event I’ve done, and was a fairly pleasant experience. The programme we were looking at was well thought out, and would clearly be a benefit to the school in question. There were the usual typos and small inconsistencies in the documentation, and we had some recommendations that might improve the student experience, particularly around assessment, where there were a lot of essays that might be replaced with some more interesting types of assessment. Overall though it looks good, and I hope they make a success of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While all that was going on, we were hosting a hackday over in Bute, a collaboration with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thebureauinvestigates.com/projects/the-bureau-local&quot;&gt;The Bureau Local&lt;/a&gt;. A team came over from &lt;a href=&quot;https://thebristolcable.org/&quot;&gt;The Bristol Cable&lt;/a&gt; and along with our students spent the day looking at voter numbers within local constituencies. I wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;http://compj.cs.cf.ac.uk/2017/05/31/hacking-voterpower-with-the-bureau-local/&quot;&gt;tiny write up&lt;/a&gt; over at the CompDJ blog, but I was a bit annoyed I couldn’t get more involved, what with everything else that was going on yesterday. Hopefully I’ll be able to get stuck in at the next one, as I’m sure this wont be the last hackday type event the Bureau organises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;thursday-1st-june&quot;&gt;Thursday 1st June&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was spent interviewing students for another of our summer projects, looking at Journalism Education. We’ve been carrying out a data collection experiment since last summer looking at the skill requirements of the media industry as exposed through job advertising and mailing list postings, and now we’re looking to back that up through a qualitative analysis of journalism school educators and their syllabi. We had 12 students from a range of schools express an interest in working on this project with us, and choosing between them is a very hard task indeed. Luckily m’colleague is leading this project, so most of that particular burden falls on him. Hopefully we’ll have someone in place very soon and we can get the third of our summer projects up and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;friday-2nd-june&quot;&gt;Friday 2nd June&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y.A.D.A.F&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;sunday-4th-june&quot;&gt;Sunday 4th June&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My ‘Friday’ was spent working on some analysis of module evaluation feedback. As I mentioned in Tuesday’s notes, we need to do more and better with the feedback given to us by students. I’ve been working for a while on creating some simple dashboards that transform the quite poor output of the module evaluation system into something that is firstly a little more usable by module leaders, but that also looks more like the survey dashboards (NSS, PTES, etc) that we are used to dealing with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://martinjc.com/img/2017-06-04-weeknotes-290517/dashboard.png&quot; alt=&quot;Module Evaluation Dashboards - WiP&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is that consistency between the types of visualisations and analysis used will reduce the cognitive burden when trying to assess the feedback and compare across surveys. I’m now starting to put together a system that will create individual dashboards for lecturers and module leaders, and that will also allow comparison between modules on the various programmes and years of our degree schemes, and allow comparison to the school as a whole. With any luck I’ll be able to present this at the next TLAQC and we can start to deliver these to lecturers and operations teams to help them understand what the students are telling them. Today was mostly refactoring my existing analysis code that takes the raw survey data and converts it into percent agree/disagree scores as per the NSS dashboards, and collects the data across the different groupings (years/programmes) of modules.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 21:00:40 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://martinjc.com//2017/06/04/weeknotes-290517.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://martinjc.com//2017/06/04/weeknotes-290517.html</guid>
        
        <category>teaching</category>
        
        <category>weeknotes</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes - 22nd May 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Strange week this week - coming back from holiday, lots of time spent catching up, arranging meetings and organising more meetings for next week&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;monday-220517&quot;&gt;Monday 22.05.17&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of Monday morning was spent dealing with all the emails I’d received while away last week. The usual mix of requests for information from admin, queries from current, potential and past students, and a number of things relating to projects that are either about to start or were supposed to have started by now! It took an absolute age to crack through it all. The apocryphal tale of the colleague who just ‘deleted everything’ on the return from holiday with the assumption that anything important would be chased up loomed large in my mind as I replied to my fiftieth message. In a world where ‘responsiveness to communication’ is one of the questions in any number of student feedback surveys, I just don’t think that path is the right one to take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday afternoon saw myself and Glyn working on our talk for Wednesday, taking the usual divide and conquer approach to put together something interesting (we hoped) for the ‘Investigating (with) Big Data’ symposium being held by the Digital Cultures Network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;tuesday-230517&quot;&gt;Tuesday 23.05.17&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another morning of marking this morning. I mentioned &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinjc.com/2017/05/15/weeknotes-140517/&quot;&gt;last week&lt;/a&gt; how pleased I was with the quality of the submissions this year, and it has held up through this latest batch too. The students really seem to have engaged with the module, have thought about what the data says and the message they want to communicate, and have then brought the technical skills to the table to implement their solution. I’m really pleased with how it’s gone. Over halfway through the marking now. It’s supposed to be done by the end of this week, but with two days of training courses and a very busy Wednesday, that’s just not going to happen. I have supplied the necessary apologies to the admin staff and I’m fairly sure they’re not going to hurt me too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The afternoon was taken up with meetings with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cardiff.ac.uk/people/view/182955-mottershead-glyn&quot;&gt;m’colleague&lt;/a&gt;, potential CUROP students, and a couple of our MSc CompDJ students who are beginning to think about their dissertation projects for this summer. One of the things Glyn and I discussed was our lack of self-promotion around the activities we do as the ‘Computational and Data Journalism’ team. In the last couple of months we’ve scored research project funding, student project funding, international workshop funding and our students have landed a number of prestigious summer internships, and we’re really not doing a good enough job at shouting about this activity. I’ve resolved to drive this forward a bit better, so came up with a list of potential items for promotion, and I’ll be trying to push those out over the summer, and then keep things ticking over during term time next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also some movement on the Untappd data project front, as I was finally pushed into responding to my co-investigators with some plans on how to progress from last year’s ICWSM conference paper to a fuller journal paper submission. This is one of those side projects that it’s a real shame to not have more time for, as I think we have a lot of interesting things that we can do, but are all lacking the time to really get stuck in to the analysis. Hopefully we’ll be able to push things forward over summer and get something delivered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;wednesday-240517&quot;&gt;Wednesday 24.05.17&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wednesday started with my first catch up meeting with the DoT for a couple of weeks. I’ve been deputy DoT since September(ish), and we’ve probably not had enough of these meetings. The plan is to make them more regular in the future, and that will probably help with keeping all the plates spinning, as I’m now working on a lot of different projects for the School. We discussed the programme approval process, as we have a number of new programmes in the pipeline as well as some changes to existing programmes going on, and we need to make sure we keep everything coherent. I’ve been tasked with setting up some meetings with the key proposers and the usual suspects within the school to make sure there’s enough coordination going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, it was over to John Percival Building to give a talk as part of the ‘Investigating (with) Big Data’ symposium. This was a double hander with m’colleague, and we’d chosen to discuss some issues around large data investigations within news media. Glyn started by presenting some of the more recent large-scale collaborative data investigations that have been carried out by news orgs. I followed that up with a discussion around data openness, transparency, and some of the technical issues that are holding back data journalism. I think the talk went well, people seemed interested and receptive to the ideas we presented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly I couldn’t hang around for the rest of the symposium as I’d double booked myself for the afternoon, having agreed to go to a briefing for exam board chairs being held over in main building. There’s a few new people taking on the exam board chair role within the school, and although I’m not one of them it was ‘decided’ (no idea who by) that I should also attend the briefing, as I’m probably going to be one of the people called upon to step in if the usual chair isn’t available. It was a fairly dull but not entirely useless presentation on the process of getting ready for and dealing with the aftermath of an exam board. It ticks the boxes though, so now I’m trained and can step into that particular set of shoes if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;thursday-250517--friday-260517&quot;&gt;Thursday 25.05.17 &amp;amp; Friday 26.05.17&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Days 2 and 3 of the ‘Leading Teaching Teams’ training programme that I’d managed to score a place on. This part of the programme was run by the Leadership Foundation for Higher Education, and was probably one of the best training courses I’ve been on so far. I spent a long time reflecting on the way I work, and it really delivered some useful insights. We did a lot of self-assessment and analysis of how our individual approaches may or may not be helpful in managing teams, and I’m looking forward to putting some of the ideas into practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with many of these training courses, one of the added benefits was being able to spend time with colleagues from across the University. It’s always fascinating to find out how others work and to hear about common problems or issues across different schools and colleges, and how they’ve been solved (or not!) in different ways. It’s also nice to get an opportunity to discuss things and to hear that others feel the same way. There was a lot of discussion and dissatisfaction expressed over the 2 days about the increased corporatisation and commodification of Higher Education. I’d love to tell you that we’ve solved that particular issue, but sadly not. Many did get righteously angry about it though. I suspect a higher societal change is needed to fix it, and all we can do at this level is to keep pushing for that change.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 21:00:40 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://martinjc.com//2017/05/28/weeknotes-220517.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://martinjc.com//2017/05/28/weeknotes-220517.html</guid>
        
        <category>teaching</category>
        
        <category>weeknotes</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes - 14th May 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A very good week this week, in that I was only in work for 3 days, but still accomplished a lot. Through some convenient meetings I’ve managed to get a whole mess of projects lined up for the next year or so, and I came out of the week on Friday very eager to get cracking on things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;monday-8517&quot;&gt;Monday 8.5.17&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week started with our Assessment and Feedback focused teaching ‘away day’, which wasn’t really an away day because we didn’t go anywhere, but which was incredibly useful nonetheless. Put together by myself, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cardiff.ac.uk/people/view/118136-jones-andrew&quot;&gt;Andrew&lt;/a&gt; (DoT) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cardiff.ac.uk/people/view/118152-phillips-helen&quot;&gt;Helen&lt;/a&gt; (A&amp;amp;F lead), the event was attended by a good number of teaching staff within the school and allowed us to spend the day thinking about our teaching practice and the way that we do things within COMSC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took a look at the upcoming Cardiff University commitments and principles around assessment and feedback, and considered how well our assessment lines up with some of the ideas within this draft of the document. A surprising amount of assessment within the school is some variation of ‘build this project in language X using paradigm Y and assess how well it performs in terms of property Z, then write a report on it’, and it turns out that trying to work out how well that corresponds with a 4,000 word essay is quite a challenge. Discussion around this topic also highlighted how the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cardiff.ac.uk/software-academy&quot;&gt;National Software Academy&lt;/a&gt; have done a good job of using larger projects as assessment for a number of different modules, something that we could do more in the BSc Computer Science, as currently there are a lot of (too many?) larger assessments within each module. Combining these makes a lot of sense - for instance why not have a software project in the first year that gets assessed for both the ‘OO Development in Java’ and the ‘Developing Quality Software’ modules, rather than a separate project in each module?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a session that I chaired we looked at Learning Outcomes of our modules - with a particular focus on how well they match with assessment or are assessable. We also looked at trying to get a handle on the year level learning outcomes for BSc Computer Science to make sure they are up to date and relevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final session of the morning saw us covering exam feedback, and how we can provide this to students in a useful fashion. The afternoon saw some discussion around a few different projects that aim to help give visibility to the workload that assessment gives to both staff and students. One project from a team in the University seemed almost useful, but focused too much on deadlines, with little regard to start dates, duration and effort. So, as a tool to help prevent deadline bunching it was great, but to actually monitor workload it was less than great. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cardiff.ac.uk/people/view/118169-theodorakopoulos-george&quot;&gt;George&lt;/a&gt; is working on a project as part of the Cardiff Futures project that promises to deliver what I think is needed (essentially automating the creation of the coursework timetables that we delivered at the beginning of this year), and hopefully that will be taken up by central University, as effective communication of this information is a key part of helping students and staff manage their workload.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;tuesday-9517&quot;&gt;Tuesday 9.5.17&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a fairly involved and in-depth Monday, Tuesday was a day of playing catch up with admin and sorting things out before my week off next week. First things first was my PDR. This was my first PDR, having come off probation last September a few months early because I was fed up of not getting paid enough. I thought it had been a pretty decent year, and Andrew seemed to agree. I agreed some interesting objectives for the next year that were basically things I’ve been wanting to do for the last few months, and are all things I’m looking forward to getting stuck in to over the next 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon I met with a few students who are interested in our summer &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cardiff.ac.uk/study/undergraduate/why-study-with-us/leaders-in-research/research-opportunities&quot;&gt;CUROP&lt;/a&gt; project doing some analysis and visualisation of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.creativecardiff.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Creative Cardiff&lt;/a&gt; data, which was fun as it’s always good to meet with interested and engaged students who are keen to get involved with research projects. Still got a couple more students to meet with, but hopefully we’ll have someone for this project relatively soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also met up with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cardiff.ac.uk/people/view/182955-mottershead-glyn&quot;&gt;m’colleague&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday afternoon and we did some more planning for the next few months. The textbook we’re writing is coming along, and we’ve identified an opportunity to get some excellent input to the book from the attendees of the Data and Computational Journalism Conference we’re organising in Dublin. We discussed the upcoming intake of students for the next academic year, and the progress our current students are making on their dissertation project pitches. We also solidified our publication plans for the next six months - with a couple of decent journal papers in the pipeline alongside a couple of decent conference presentations it’s looking like a strong finish to the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;wednesday-10517&quot;&gt;Wednesday 10.5.17&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a day off today to have a sneaky date with my wife for her birthday (which isn’t really until later this month). We went off to the theatre to watch OmiDaze doing Romeo and Juliet, which was very enjoyable, then to a bar in the bay for lunch which was very tasty (food) and very average (beer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;thursday-11517&quot;&gt;Thursday 11.5.17&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worked from home today ploughing through the CMT212 marking. The quality this year is incredibly high, and I’m very pleased with how the students have analysed and visualised their data. I’ve had a few students submitting data analysis in R, a lot of Python, and then the majority of the visualisation so far has been some very good D3 code. If the standard keeps up across the whole cohort when I get round to marking the rest I’ll be very happy indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;friday-12517&quot;&gt;Friday 12.5.17&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nada. Day off again (2 in 1 week!) packing and preparing for the week off. Mad day rushing around with Arthur collecting parcels, packing bags, and trying to optimise the fitting of bags into the car boot so that we could get both ourselves and the luggage in the car at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 21:13:40 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://martinjc.com//2017/05/15/weeknotes-140517.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://martinjc.com//2017/05/15/weeknotes-140517.html</guid>
        
        <category>teaching</category>
        
        <category>pedagogy</category>
        
        <category>weeknotes</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scraping the Assembly</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;M’colleague is currently teaching a first-semester module on Data Journalism to the students on our MSc in Computational and Data Journalism. As part of this, they need to do some sort of data project. One of the students is looking at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://allowances.assembly.wales/Default.aspx?Option=switch&quot;&gt;expenses of Welsh Assembly Members&lt;/a&gt;. These are all freely available online, but not in an easy to manipulate form. According to the Assembly they’d be happy to give the data out as a spreadsheet, if we submitted an FOI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, this seems quite stupid. The information is all online and freely accessible. You’ve admitted you’re willing to give it out to anyone who submits an FOI. So why not just make the raw data available to download? This does not sound like a helpful &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opengovernment.org.uk/about/&quot;&gt;Open Government&lt;/a&gt; to me. Anyway, for whatever reason, they’ve chosen not to, and we can’t be bothered to wait around for an FOI to come back. It’s much quicker and easier to build a scraper! We’ll just use selenium to drive a web browser, submit a search, page through all the results collecting the details, then dump it all out to csv. Simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://martinjc.com/img/2016-11-02-scraping-the-assembly/out.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Scraping AM expenses&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built this as a quick hack this morning. It took about an hour or so, and it shows. The code is not robust in any way, but it works. You can ask it for data from any year (or a number of years) and it’ll happily sit there churning its way through the results and spitting them out as both .csv and .json.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the code is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/martinjc/assembly-expenses-scraper&quot;&gt;available on Github&lt;/a&gt; and it’s under an MIT Licence. Have fun 😉&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 20:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://martinjc.com//2016/11/02/scraping-the-assembly.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://martinjc.com//2016/11/02/scraping-the-assembly.html</guid>
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        <category>data</category>
        
        <category>development</category>
        
        <category>expenses</category>
        
        <category>scraping</category>
        
        <category>python</category>
        
        <category>selenium</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Atom Plugins for Web Development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a number of students in my web-dev module asking me what plugins I’m using in my text editor, so I thought I’d dash off a quick blog post on the plugins I find useful day-to-day. (Actually, most people are normally asking me ‘how did you do that thing where you typed one word and suddenly you had a whole HTML page? The answer is I used a plugin, so ‘what plugins do you use?’ is really the question they should be asking…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m using &lt;a href=&quot;https://atom.io/&quot;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt; as my text editor. It’s free, open source, and generally reliable. If you’re a student on my web-dev course you’re stuck using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/&quot;&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/a&gt; in the lab for now. I’m pretty sure most of the Atom plugins I use have either direct Sublime equivalents, or similarly functioning alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a guide to Atom packages &lt;a href=&quot;here&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and one for Sublime Text &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/docs/3/packages.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick google for ‘best atom packages web developer’ will probably get you to a far more comprehensive list than this, but here’s my current pick of useful plugins anyway:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;emmet&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://atom.io/packages/emmet&quot;&gt;emmet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is essential for anyone writing any amount of HTML. This is the magic package that allows me to write ‘html:5’ in a blank document, hit the shortcut keys (CTRL + E in my setup), and suddenly have a simple boilerplate HTML page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://martinjc.com/img/2016-10-05-atom-plugins-for-web-development/out.gif&quot; alt=&quot;emmet auto-completion&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s ace. Not only that, but it can write loads of HTML for you, and all you have to do is write a CSS selector for that HTML:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://martinjc.com/img/2016-10-05-atom-plugins-for-web-development/out-1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;html css Selector expansion&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great stuff. The documentation is here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;atom-beautify&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://atom.io/packages/atom-beautify&quot;&gt;atom-beautify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will tidy up your code automatically, fixing the indentation and spacing etc. It can even be set to automatically tidy your code every time you save a file. Awesome huh? Imagine being set a coursework where some of the marks were dependent on not writing code that looks like it was written by a five-year old child who’s addicted to hitting the tab key, then finding out that there’s software to strap that five-year olds thumbs to his hands so he can’t hit that tab key. Awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://martinjc.com/img/2016-10-05-atom-plugins-for-web-development/out-2.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Beautiful tidy code&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;color-picker&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://atom.io/packages/color-picker&quot;&gt;color-picker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one adds a colour picker right into atom. Just CMD-SHIFT-C and choose your colours!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://martinjc.com/img/2016-10-05-atom-plugins-for-web-development/out-3.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Colour picker&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another useful colour related plugin you may want to look at is Pigments, which can highlight colours in your projects, and gather them all together so you can see your palette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;linter&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://atom.io/packages/linter&quot;&gt;linter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My last recommendation is linter. This plugin will automatically check your code for errors. You’ll need to install linters for whatever language you want to check, like linter-tidy, linter-csslint, linter-pylint and linter-jshint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://martinjc.com/img/2016-10-05-atom-plugins-for-web-development/Screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Linter finds errors in your code&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there we go – a few recommendations to get you started. Found anything else interesting? Let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 21:17:40 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://martinjc.com//2016/10/05/atom-plugins-for-web-development.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://martinjc.com//2016/10/05/atom-plugins-for-web-development.html</guid>
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        <category>d3</category>
        
        <category>visualisation</category>
        
        <category>workshop</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sustainable Software Institute – Research Data Visualisation Workshop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I  gave a talk and delivered a hands on session at the Sustainable Software Institute’s ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.software.ac.uk/rdvw&quot;&gt;Research Data Visualisation Workshop&lt;/a&gt;‘ which was held at Manchester University. It was a really engaging event, with a lot of good discussion on the issues surrounding data visualisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iidi.napier.ac.uk/c/people/peopleid/41&quot;&gt;Professor Jessie Kennedy&lt;/a&gt; from Edinburgh Napier University gave a great keynote looking at a some key design principles in visualisation, including a number of studies I hadn’t seen before but will definitely be including in my teaching in future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk on ‘Human Science Visualisation’ which really focused on a couple of key issues. Firstly, I tried to illustrate the importance of interactivity in complex visualisations. I then talked about how we as academic researchers need publish our interactive visualisations in posterity, and how we should press academic publishers to help us communicate our data to readers. Finally, I wanted to point people towards the excellent visualisation work being done by data journalists, and that the newsrooms are an excellent source of ideas and tips for data visualisation. The slides for my talk are here. It’s the first time I’ve spoken about visualisation outside of the classroom, and it was a really fun talk to give.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also had two great talks from &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/site/chbergma/&quot;&gt;Dr Christina Bergmann&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://andysouth.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Dr Andy South&lt;/a&gt;, focusing on issues of biological visualisation and mapping respectively. All the talks generated some good discussion both in the room and online, which was fantastic to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon I lead a hands on session looking at visualising data using d3. This was the first time I’d taught a session using d3 v4, which made things slightly interesting. I’m not fully up to speed with all the areas of the API that have changed, so getting the live coding right first time was a bit tricky, but I think I managed. Interestingly, I feel that the changes made to the .data(), .exit(), .enter(), update cycle as discussed in Mike’s “&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mbostock/what-makes-software-good-943557f8a488&quot;&gt;What Makes Software Good&lt;/a&gt;” make a lot more sense from a teaching perspective. The addition of .merge() in particular helps a great deal. As you might expect from a d3 workshop that lasted a mere three hours, I’m not entirely convinced that everybody ‘got’ it, but I think a most went away satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall it was a very successful workshop. &lt;a href=&quot;http://rgaiacs.com/&quot;&gt;Raniere Silva&lt;/a&gt; did an excellent job putting it together and running the day, and I really enjoyed it. I’m looking forward to seeing what other people thought about it too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 21:17:40 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://martinjc.com//2016/08/01/sustainable-software-institute-research-data-visualisation-workshop.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://martinjc.com//2016/08/01/sustainable-software-institute-research-data-visualisation-workshop.html</guid>
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        <category>d3</category>
        
        <category>visualisation</category>
        
        <category>workshop</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quick Update...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Been a bit quiet here recently. It’s been a very busy few months. I’ve got a few projects and thoughts that I’ll be posting more on in the next couple of weeks, but I figured it was worth a quick update on what’s been going on, and what I’ve been up to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;msc-computational-journalism&quot;&gt;MSc Computational Journalism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have finished the taught part of the MSc, and we’re getting well into the dissertation phase for the first cohort of our students. It’s been a really good first year, and I’ll be posting a debrief and some thoughts on the next year sometime over summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bardiff&quot;&gt;BarDiff&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve launched a &lt;a href=&quot;http://bardiff.martinjc.com&quot;&gt;data dashboard thing for beer drinking in Cardiff&lt;/a&gt;. Powered by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.untappd.com&quot;&gt;Untappd&lt;/a&gt; checkins, it’s providing (I think) a fairly interesting overview of the city. I’ve got some ideas for some better visualisations, but for now it’s nicely ticking over. Plus it’s getting some decent interaction on the social medias&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;academia&quot;&gt;Academia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The usual ticking over of academia continues - journal reviews, conference reviews,  a book chapter to write, paper deadlines coming and going. It’s the same old same old….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;teaching&quot;&gt;Teaching&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve started on my teaching qualification (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cardiff.ac.uk/pcutl/&quot;&gt;PgCUTL&lt;/a&gt;). The first module portfolio was submitted a couple of weeks ago, and results are due any day now (fingers crossed). I’ve also got a few thoughts on the recently announced TEF that I’ll be putting up soon, and some things on employability…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-finally&quot;&gt;and finally…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I’ve not posted in a while:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://martinjc.com/img/2015-07-13-quick-update/11325423_448026158711440_20867902_n-1024x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Arthur!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My son, Arthur James Chorley-Jones was born on 13th May 2015. He’s amazing, I think he’s the best thing that has ever happened, and since he’s been around there has not been a huge amount of time for blogging, side-projects, and other such things. Which is ace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 21:17:40 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://martinjc.com//2015/07/13/quick-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://martinjc.com//2015/07/13/quick-update.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Accessing and Scraping MyFitnessPal Data with Python</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Interesting news this morning that MyFitnessPal has been bought by Under Armour for  $475 million. I’ve used MFP for many years now, and it was pretty helpful in helping me lose all the excess PhD weight that I’d put on, and then maintaining a healthy(ish) lifestyle since 2010.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;News of an acquisition always has me slightly worried though - not for someone else having access to my data, as I’ve made my peace with the fact that using a free service generally means that it’s me that’s being sold. Giving away my data is the cost of doing business. Rather, it worries me that I may lose access to all the data I’ve collected. I have no idea what Under Armour intend for the service in the long run, and while its likely that MFP will continue with business as usual for the foreseeable, it’s always worth having a backup of your data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://martinjc.com/2011/06/09/logging-in-to-websites-with-python/&quot;&gt;A few years ago, I wrote a couple of python scripts&lt;/a&gt; to back up data from MFP and then extract the food and exercise info from the raw HTML. These scripts use Python and Beautiful Soup to do a login to MFP, then go back through your diary history and save all the raw HTML pages, essentially scraping your data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came to run them this morning and found they needed a couple of changes to deal with site updates. I’ve made the necessary updates and the full code for all the scripts is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/martinjc/mfp-scraper&quot;&gt;available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. It’s not great, but it works. The code is Python 2 and requires BeautifulSoup and Matplotlib (if you want to use generate_plots.py).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 11:02:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://martinjc.com//2015/02/05/accessing-and-scraping-myfitnesspal-data-with-python.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://martinjc.com//2015/02/05/accessing-and-scraping-myfitnesspal-data-with-python.html</guid>
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        <category>data</category>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        <category>lifelogging</category>
        
        <category>mfp</category>
        
        <category>python</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Personality and Places</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0747563214007559&quot;&gt;Our paper&lt;/a&gt; examining the link between &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinjc.com/2012/11/20/foursquare-personality-experiment/&quot;&gt;individual personality and the places people visit&lt;/a&gt; has just been published in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.journals.elsevier.com/computers-in-human-behavior/&quot;&gt;Computers in Human Behavior&lt;/a&gt;. It’s open access, so you can &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.chb.2014.12.038&quot;&gt;go read it for free, now&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an experiment we ran previously, we asked users of Foursquare to take a personality test and give us access to their checkin history. The personality test gives us a measure of how each person scores for five different factors: Openness, Conscientiousness, Extraversion, Agreeableness and Neuroticism. The checkin history lists all the places they’ve ever checked in to using Foursquare. Because a couple of hundred people took part in the experiment, we ended up with a large number of individual personalities that we could link to over a hundred thousand venues. In total, this represents a pretty staggering half a million Foursquare checkins that we have personality data associated with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first step with this data has been to see if there are any links between personality factors and the places people choose to visit, and we found some interesting connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our main finding shows that the use of Foursquare for recording checkins seems to correlate well with Conscientiousness. &lt;strong&gt;The more conscientious a user is, the more likely they are to have checked in at more places and to have visited more venues.&lt;/strong&gt; This could be because people with a high Conscientiousness score tend to be quite organised and disciplined, and so are more likely to remember to check in at every place they visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opposite is true for Neuroticism: &lt;strong&gt;the more neurotic an individual is, the fewer places they have visited&lt;/strong&gt;. Neuroticism is associated with negative feelings, and a tendency to be less social, which could then translate into people going to fewer places, and so checking in less. This is expressed again when we look at only those venues classed as ‘social’ (i.e. - somewhere you would go to hang out with friends). &lt;strong&gt;The more neurotic someone is, the fewer ‘social’ venues they have been to.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, we have found no link between Extraversion and the number of social venues visited. It may be expected that extraverts (who are very social in their nature) may go to more social venues. However, the data does not support this. In fact, &lt;strong&gt;we find no link between Extraversion and any aspect of Foursquare checkins&lt;/strong&gt; that we have examined so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The personality factor of Openness is related to feelings of creativity and artistic expression, and a willingness to experience new things. It is interesting to find that there is a link between Openness and the average distance travelled between checkins -** the more Open an individual is, the further they tend to have travelled**. This could be an expression of an Open individual’s desire to experience new things exposing itself through wider travel, and a larger geographic spread of checkins. However, we do not find any link between Openness and the number of different categories visited by a user. We do not see a desire for new experiences express itself in the range and diversity of places visited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, this data could be incredibly useful in improving venue recommendation systems. Current systems use many different information ‘cues’ to recommend to a user a place they might like to visit. These cues include things such as where they have been in the past, where their friends have been, or where is popular nearby. Perhaps by including aspects of an individual’s personality (so including aspects of &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; they might visit somewhere) we can increase the usefulness of these recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is still a lot of analysis to be done on this data, and both myself and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.cf.ac.uk/contactsandpeople/staffpage.php?emailname=NoeN&quot;&gt;Nyala Noe&lt;/a&gt; are busy churning through it to discover other links between personality and the places people visit. As we find more interesting connections, I’ll post more here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 11:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://martinjc.com//2015/01/27/personality-and-places.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://martinjc.com//2015/01/27/personality-and-places.html</guid>
        
        <category>foursquare</category>
        
        <category>open access</category>
        
        <category>paper</category>
        
        <category>personality</category>
        
        <category>psychology</category>
        
        <category>publication</category>
        
        <category>research</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NHS Hackday 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend I took part in an incredibly successful &lt;a href=&quot;http://nhshackday.com/&quot;&gt;NHS hackday&lt;/a&gt;, hosted at Cardiff University and organised by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/amcunningham&quot;&gt;Anne Marie Cunningham&lt;/a&gt; and James Morgan. We went as a team from the MSc in Computational Journalism, with myself and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/egrommet&quot;&gt;Glyn&lt;/a&gt; attending along with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PoojaDante&quot;&gt;Pooja&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NikitaVashisth&quot;&gt;Nikita&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Idioteque90&quot;&gt;Annalisa&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cboutaud&quot;&gt;Charles&lt;/a&gt;. At the last-minute I recruited a couple of ringers as well, dragging along &lt;del&gt;Rhys Priestland&lt;/del&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/flyingSparx&quot;&gt;Dr William Wilberforce Webberley&lt;/a&gt; from Comsc and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/voxmjw&quot;&gt;Dr Matthew Williams&lt;/a&gt;, previously of this parish. Annalisa also brought along Dan Hewitt, so in total we had a large and diverse team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-hackday&quot;&gt;The hackday&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the first NHS hackday I’d attended, but I believe it’s the second event held in Cardiff, so Anne Marie and the team have it down to a fine art. The whole weekend seemed to go pretty smoothly (barring a couple of misunderstandings on our part regarding the pitch sessions!). It was certainly one of the most well organised events that I’ve attended, with all the necessary ingredients for successful coding: much power, many wifi and plenty of food, snacks and coffee. Anne Marie and the team deserve much recognition and thanks for their hard work. I’m definitely in for next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quality of the projects created at the hackday was incredibly high across the board, which was great to see. One of my favourites used an Oculus Rift virtual reality headset to create a zombie ‘game’ that could be used to test people’s peripheral vision. Another standout was a system for logging and visualising the ANGEL factors describing a patient’s health situation. It was really pleasing to see these rank highly with the judges too, coming in third and second in the overall rankings. Other great projects brought an old Open Source project back to life, created a system for managing groups walking the Wales Coast path, and created automatic notification systems for healthcare processes. Overall it was a really interesting mix of projects, many of which have clear potential to become useful products within or alongside the NHS. As Matt commented in the pub afterwards, it’s probably the first hackday we’ve been to where several of the projects have clear original IP with commercial potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ourproject&quot;&gt;Our project&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had decided before the event that we wanted to build some visualisations of health data across Wales, something like &lt;a href=&quot;http://nhsmaps.co.uk/&quot;&gt;nhsmaps.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;, but working with local health boards and local authorities in Wales. We split into two teams for the implementation: ‘the data team’ who were responsible for sourcing, processing and inputting data, and the ‘interface team’ who built the front-end and the visualisations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Progress was good, with Matthew and William quickly defining a schema for describing data so that the data team could add multiple data sets and have the front-end automatically pick them up and be able to visualise them. The CompJ students worked to find and extract data, adding them to the github repository with the correct metadata. Meanwhile, I pulled a bunch of D3 code together for some simple visualisations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of the weekend we established a fairly decent system. It’s able to visualise a few different types of data, at different resolutions, is mostly mobile friendly, and most importantly is easily extensible and adaptable. It’s online now on our &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/hewnhs&quot;&gt;github pages&lt;/a&gt;, and all the code and documentation is also in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/compjcdf/nhs_hack&quot;&gt;github repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll continue development for a while to improve the usability and code quality, and hopefully we’ll find a community willing to take the code base on and keep improving what could be a fairly useful resource for understanding the health of Wales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;debrief&quot;&gt;Debrief&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t win any of the prizes, which is understandable. Our project was really focused on the public understanding of the NHS and health, and not for solving a particular need within (or for users of) the NHS. We knew this going in to the weekend, and we’d taken the decision that it was more important to work on a project related to the course, so that the students could experience some of the tools and technologies they’ll be using as the course progresses than to do something more closely aligned with the brief that would have perhaps been less relevant to the students work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to thank Will and Matt for coming and helping the team. Without Matt wrangling the data team and showing them how to create json metadata descriptors we probably wouldn’t have anywhere near as many example datasets as we do. Similarly, without Will’s hard work on the front end interface, the project wouldn’t look nearly as good as it does, or have anywhere near the functionality. His last-minute addition of localstorage for personal datasets was a triumph. (Sadly though he does lose some coder points for user agent sniffing to decide whether to show a mobile interface :-D.) They were both a massive help, and we couldn’t have done it without them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, of course, I need to congratulate the CompJ students, who gave up their weekend to trawl through datasets, pull figures off websites and out of pdf’s, and create the lovely easy to process .csv files we needed. It was a great effort from them, and I’m looking forward to our next Team CompJ hackday outing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that sadly did stand out was a lack of participation from Comsc undergraduate students, with only one or two attending. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.cf.ac.uk/contactsandpeople/staffpage.php?emailname=Rob.Davies&quot;&gt;Rob Davies&lt;/a&gt; stopped by on Saturday, and both Will and I discussed with him what we can do to increase participation in these events. Hopefully we’ll make some progress on that front in time for the next hackday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;media&quot;&gt;Media&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s some great photos from the event on Flickr, courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/paul_clarke/&quot;&gt;Paul Clarke&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/paul_clarke/sets/72157650042039338/&quot;&gt;Saturday&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/paul_clarke/sets/72157650456182132/&quot;&gt;Sunday&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;elsewhere&quot;&gt;Elsewhere…&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got a lovely &lt;a href=&quot;https://goodpracticeexchange.wordpress.com/2015/01/24/nhs-hack-day-data-visualisation/&quot;&gt;write-up about out project&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DyfrigWilliams&quot;&gt;Dyfrig Williams&lt;/a&gt; of the Good Practice Exchange at the Wales Audit Office. Dyfrig also curated a great &lt;a href=&quot;https://storify.com/GoodPracticeWAO/nhs-hack-day-cardiff-2015&quot;&gt;storify of the weekend&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hemavault labs have done a round up of the projects &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.hemavault.com/2015/01/27/nhs-hack-day-cardiff-2015-projects/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 10:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://martinjc.com//2015/01/26/nhs-hackday-2015.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://martinjc.com//2015/01/26/nhs-hackday-2015.html</guid>
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        <category>compj</category>
        
        <category>data</category>
        
        <category>development</category>
        
        <category>github</category>
        
        <category>hackathon</category>
        
        <category>javascript</category>
        
        <category>opensource</category>
        
        <category>visualisation</category>
        
        <category>web</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
