<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Holiday on Martin Chorley</title>
    <link>/tags/holiday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Holiday on Martin Chorley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 12:40:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/holiday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Edinburgh Festival... Day Five</title>
      <link>/2011/09/08/edinburgh-festival...-day-five/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 12:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/08/edinburgh-festival...-day-five/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s the last full day at the festival and we wake up even later than the day before. It&amp;rsquo;s so late we decide to skip breakfast, and as it&amp;rsquo;s time for lunch we&amp;rsquo;ll head out for curry. A quick curry and rice and we&amp;rsquo;re up and running for the day once more. The shows today don&amp;rsquo;t start until later on, so we have a bit of a walk around, grab a coffee and cake, then once more split, as Lisa decides to go back to the flat briefly while I head to pub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edinburgh Festival... Day Four</title>
      <link>/2011/09/08/edinburgh-festival...-day-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 08:56:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/08/edinburgh-festival...-day-four/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday we wake up later than intended, so miss the planned start to the day at the Shakespeare breakfast. In all, it&amp;rsquo;s a very slow start to the day, the pace of the previous few days is beginning to get to us. We head off for a walk and a bagel to wake up, and I get butter all over my face from a very lovely, but very buttery and bacon filled bagel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edinburgh Festival... Day Three</title>
      <link>/2011/09/07/edinburgh-festival...-day-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 06:23:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/07/edinburgh-festival...-day-three/</guid>
      <description>Success today as we start the day with a run round the meadows, despite all the beer yesterday. A &amp;lsquo;debate&amp;rsquo; which I lose ends in us also running around the links and up towards Warrender Park Crescent. The flat I stayed in during my second stint in Edinburgh for the MSc was there, so it was nice to be running around the old stomping ground.
After the run I bump into another Shrewsbury Town fan outside tesco&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edinburgh Festival... Day Two</title>
      <link>/2011/09/05/edinburgh-festival...-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2011 06:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/05/edinburgh-festival...-day-two/</guid>
      <description>Day two began with the best intentions - I woke up early, fully intending to go for a run around the meadows. It only took about thirty seconds of being awake for me to realise that wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to happen, so I went back to sleep for another hour. By about 8.30 the waking up was really beginning to take hold, so we relented and got up.
Usual morning operations completed (including Lisa having to conclude delicate negotiations with reception for the use of a hairdryer), we headed out into town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edinburgh Festival... Day One (The Shows)</title>
      <link>/2011/08/25/edinburgh-festival...-day-one-the-shows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 20:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/08/25/edinburgh-festival...-day-one-the-shows/</guid>
      <description>Our first show was Dave Gorman at Assembly at the George Square Lecture Theatre, so after checking in we headed straight over there. We sat in the sun on the steps outside the venue and supped a couple of pints of Deuchars. We shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have bothered, it was served so cold you couldn&amp;rsquo;t taste anything, although maybe that was a blessing seeing as it came from a bar inside a shipping container and was served in a plastic cup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edinburgh 2011.... Day One (The Journey)</title>
      <link>/2011/08/25/edinburgh-2011....-day-one-the-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 19:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/08/25/edinburgh-2011....-day-one-the-journey/</guid>
      <description>Despite having lived in Edinburgh for almost a year on and off while doing my MSc, I&amp;rsquo;ve never been up there at festival time. We decided to rectify this, so earlier on in the year (way earlier on in the year) we booked some accommodation for the second week of the festival and made our plans to hit the city for a festival holiday. Over a few posts I&amp;rsquo;ll describe in laborious detail what we did, what we saw, and what we (or I) thought of it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>