<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visualisation on Martin Chorley</title>
    <link>/tags/visualisation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visualisation on Martin Chorley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 20:17:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/visualisation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Atom Plugins for Web Development</title>
      <link>/2016/10/05/atom-plugins-for-web-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 20:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/05/atom-plugins-for-web-development/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had a number of students in my web-dev module asking me what plugins I’m using in my text editor, so I thought I’d dash off a quick blog post on the plugins I find useful day-to-day. (Actually, most people are normally asking me ‘how did you do that thing where you typed one word and suddenly you had a whole HTML page? The answer is I used a plugin, so ‘what plugins do you use?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Software Institute – Research Data Visualisation Workshop</title>
      <link>/2016/08/01/sustainable-software-institute-research-data-visualisation-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 20:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/08/01/sustainable-software-institute-research-data-visualisation-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Last week I gave a talk and delivered a hands on session at the Sustainable Software Institute’s ‘Research Data Visualisation Workshop‘ which was held at Manchester University. It was a really engaging event, with a lot of good discussion on the issues surrounding data visualisation.
Professor Jessie Kennedy from Edinburgh Napier University gave a great keynote looking at a some key design principles in visualisation, including a number of studies I hadn’t seen before but will definitely be including in my teaching in future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NHS Hackday 2015</title>
      <link>/2015/01/26/nhs-hackday-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 10:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/01/26/nhs-hackday-2015/</guid>
      <description>This weekend I took part in an incredibly successful NHS hackday, hosted at Cardiff University and organised by Anne Marie Cunningham and James Morgan. We went as a team from the MSc in Computational Journalism, with myself and Glyn attending along with Pooja, Nikita, Annalisa and Charles. At the last-minute I recruited a couple of ringers as well, dragging along Rhys Priestland Dr William Wilberforce Webberley from Comsc and Dr Matthew Williams, previously of this parish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CompJ Labs - Postcodes</title>
      <link>/2015/01/05/compj-labs-postcodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 09:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/01/05/compj-labs-postcodes/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve thrown up a post on compj.cs.cf.ac.uk about some work we&amp;rsquo;ve done looking at empty properties in Cardiff. I&amp;rsquo;ll add further posts over the coming weeks about other data analysis we&amp;rsquo;ve done on this topic, and new work looking at the Welsh Assembly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GeoJSON and topoJSON for UK boundaries</title>
      <link>/2014/09/17/geojson-and-topojson-for-uk-boundaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 10:05:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/09/17/geojson-and-topojson-for-uk-boundaries/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just put an archive online containing GeoJSON and topoJSON for UK boundary data. It&amp;rsquo;s all stored on Github, with a viewer and download site hosted on Github pages.
   Browser for the UK topoJSON stored in the Github repository    The data is all created from shapefiles released by the Office of National Statistics, Ordnance Survey and National Records Scotland, all under the Open Government and OS OpenData licences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Graphical Web 2014</title>
      <link>/2014/09/04/the-graphical-web-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 10:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/09/04/the-graphical-web-2014/</guid>
      <description>photo of the author outside Winchester cathedral    Last week I had a lovely time down in Winchester with m&amp;rsquo;colleague, attending The Graphical Web 2014. This year the theme was &amp;lsquo;Visual Storytelling&amp;rsquo;, so I&amp;rsquo;d gone along to see what new things we could learn about visualisation to include in the MSc in Computational Journalism. We&amp;rsquo;d also already had a few conversations about the course with people who were going to be at the conference, so we were planning to take the opportunity to chat in person about their involvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>not another bloody wordle?!?!</title>
      <link>/2013/08/20/not-another-bloody-wordle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 08:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/20/not-another-bloody-wordle/</guid>
      <description>(UPDATE: an earlier version of this was totally wrong. It&amp;rsquo;s better now.)
Inspired by a Facebook post from a colleague, I decided to waste ten minutes this week knocking together a word cloud from the text of my thesis. The process was pretty straightforward.
First up - extracting the text from the thesis. Like all good scienticians, my thesis was written in LaTeX. I thought I could have used a couple of different tools to extract the plain text from the raw .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Project update</title>
      <link>/2013/07/25/summer-project-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 13:23:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/07/25/summer-project-update/</guid>
      <description>We are storming along with summer projects now, and starting to see some really good results.
Liam Turner (who is starting a PhD in the school in October) has been working hard to create a mobile version of the 4SQPersonality app. His work is coming along really well, with a great mobile HTML version now up and running, a native android wrapper working, and an iOS wrapper on its way. With any luck we&amp;rsquo;ll have mobile apps for both major platforms ready to be released before the summer is over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SWN Artist Explorer</title>
      <link>/2012/10/04/swn-artist-explorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 09:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/10/04/swn-artist-explorer/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of year again: SWN Festival is once more upon us. It&amp;rsquo;s the highlight of the musical year in Cardiff, and probably the one thing I&amp;rsquo;ll miss about the city when (if?) I leave. In fact, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty certain that even if I left the city I&amp;rsquo;d make the pilgrimage back once a year for SWN because it&amp;rsquo;s just too much fun to miss.
The lineup this year is another cracking one, but as usual with four days of bands spread across so many venues there are a whole bunch of names that I don&amp;rsquo;t recognise.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>