<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diet on Martin Chorley</title>
    <link>https://martinjc.com/tags/diet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Diet on Martin Chorley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 08:07:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://martinjc.com/tags/diet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping data from MyFitnessPal with python</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/06/09/scraping-data-from-myfitnesspal-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 08:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/06/09/scraping-data-from-myfitnesspal-with-python/</guid>
      <description>Following my success with extracting my Google Search History in a simple manner, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that I should do something similar to extract all the data I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeding into myfitnesspal for the last 5 months. As I briefly mentioned in the review of the app + website, the progress graphs leave a lot to be desired and there&amp;rsquo;s very little in the way of analysis of the data. I have a lot of questions about my progress and there is no easy way to answer all of them using just the website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing Weight in 2011 continued... Libra</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/06/08/losing-weight-in-2011-continued...-libra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 21:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/06/08/losing-weight-in-2011-continued...-libra/</guid>
      <description>Another of the very useful apps I&amp;rsquo;ve been using since the start of the &amp;ldquo;New Regime&amp;rdquo; is Libra. It totally makes up for the crappy progress graphs on the MyFitnessPal website or in the mobile app.
It&amp;rsquo;s an app that has a singular purpose: it&amp;rsquo;s just for tracking weight. But it does it very well. You enter a weight for every day, it works out statistics based on those weights, calculates the trend value for your weight, (so smoothes out daily fluctuations caused by water intake etc), and predicts when you&amp;rsquo;ll hit your target.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing Weight in 2011 continued... My Fitness Pal</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/06/07/losing-weight-in-2011-continued...-my-fitness-pal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 08:01:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/06/07/losing-weight-in-2011-continued...-my-fitness-pal/</guid>
      <description>(The first in a series of posts on apps I&amp;rsquo;ve found useful under &amp;lsquo;the new regime&amp;rsquo;)
One of the best apps/services I&amp;rsquo;ve found for general fitness and nutrition and weight loss is MyFitnessPal. I&amp;rsquo;m fairly sure I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have made quite as good progress without it.
The main selling point of the service is that it allows you to track what you eat and what exercise you do, in order to monitor and help regulate your calorific intake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing weight in 2011</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/06/05/losing-weight-in-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2011 16:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/06/05/losing-weight-in-2011/</guid>
      <description>Since the beginning of the year I&amp;rsquo;ve been living under what we&amp;rsquo;ve been calling &amp;lsquo;the new regime&amp;rsquo;. This &amp;lsquo;new regime&amp;rsquo; basically involves not living like a fat useless slob, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting fit, eating healthily and losing weight. So far I&amp;rsquo;ve lost over 10kg and can now run around the park a few times without collapsing to the floor clutching at my chest and screaming about ambulances, so I&amp;rsquo;d say its going pretty well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>