<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Martin Chorley</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Martin Chorley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 11:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic Parent</title>
      <link>/2017/11/29/academic-parent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/29/academic-parent/</guid>
      <description>I, like many others, made note of a recent tweet by Nathan Hall discussing the attitude of his colleagues when he prioritises family over career:
I still find it interesting the puzzled expressions I get from colleagues when mentioning how childcare impacts my academic work; when explaining why I try to minimize conference travel, leave the office by 4 PM, or sometimes cancel meetings due to dad responsibilities.
&amp;mdash; Nathan C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataJConf Debrief</title>
      <link>/2017/08/05/datajconf-debrief/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/05/datajconf-debrief/</guid>
      <description>DataJConf at UCD    A month ago we held the first European Data and Computational Journalism Conference in Dublin, Ireland. This is a long overdue post about that event.
The conference idea started as all good ideas do, in the pub and with a tweet. It was at a social event during ICWSM &amp;lsquo;16 where I was first introduced to Bahareh Heravi, a data journalism lecturer from UCD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-Graduation Thoughts</title>
      <link>/2017/08/04/post-graduation-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 14:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/04/post-graduation-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Last month I took part in my first graduation ceremony as part of the academic procession. This is the bit where staff members from the school(s) that are graduating get dressed up in their silly robes, &amp;lsquo;process&amp;rsquo; into the graduation ceremony, and sit on stage for an hour or so clapping as all their students stride across the stage to shake the VC&amp;rsquo;s hand and graduate from their degree.
It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fun, because who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like dressing up in silly robes and a hat?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 20:22:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>I am the Director of Learning and Teaching (DLT) for the School of Computer Science and Informatics. For the last few years I&amp;rsquo;ve been the Deputy DLT, and have spent a lot of time focused on Postgraduate students, working as the chair of the Postgraduate Operations Team, Senior Personal Tutor for Taught Postgraduate students, and the Student Rep Coordinator for the postgrad Student-Staff Panel.
I&amp;rsquo;m the MSc Programme Leader for the MSc in Computational and Data Journalism, a joint course between the School of Computer Science &amp;amp; Informatics and the School of Journalism, Media and Culture here at Cardiff University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 11:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>A large focus of my current research is in the area of Computational and Data Journalism, including studying Data Journalism and Computer Science education. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in the understanding of educational methods (including the use of innovative teaching and assessment) particularly within STEM subjects, but also at the cross-disciplinary boundary.
I like doing research wherever computer science, IT systems and devices brush up against the real world, as things are far more interesting when people are involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>A list of my publications is given below, it&amp;rsquo;s usually fairly up to date. Alternatively, you can take a look at my Google Scholar profile, or my profile on any number of useless &amp;ldquo;academic profile&amp;rdquo; websites (listed at the end of the page).
Journal Articles  Margeret Hall, Athanasios Mazarakis, Martin Chorley, Simon Caton,  2018  &#34;Editorial of the special issue on following user pathways: Key contributions and future directions in cross-platform social media research&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>