<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coding on Martin Chorley</title>
    <link>https://martinjc.com/tags/coding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coding on Martin Chorley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 20:17:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://martinjc.com/tags/coding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping the Assembly</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2016/11/02/scraping-the-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 20:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2016/11/02/scraping-the-assembly/</guid>
      <description>M’colleague is currently teaching a first-semester module on Data Journalism to the students on our MSc in Computational and Data Journalism. As part of this, they need to do some sort of data project. One of the students is looking at the expenses of Welsh Assembly Members. These are all freely available online, but not in an easy to manipulate form. According to the Assembly they’d be happy to give the data out as a spreadsheet, if we submitted an FOI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atom Plugins for Web Development</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2016/10/05/atom-plugins-for-web-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 20:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2016/10/05/atom-plugins-for-web-development/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had a number of students in my web-dev module asking me what plugins I’m using in my text editor, so I thought I’d dash off a quick blog post on the plugins I find useful day-to-day. (Actually, most people are normally asking me ‘how did you do that thing where you typed one word and suddenly you had a whole HTML page? The answer is I used a plugin, so ‘what plugins do you use?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Software Institute – Research Data Visualisation Workshop</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2016/08/01/sustainable-software-institute-research-data-visualisation-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 20:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2016/08/01/sustainable-software-institute-research-data-visualisation-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Last week I gave a talk and delivered a hands on session at the Sustainable Software Institute’s ‘Research Data Visualisation Workshop‘ which was held at Manchester University. It was a really engaging event, with a lot of good discussion on the issues surrounding data visualisation.
Professor Jessie Kennedy from Edinburgh Napier University gave a great keynote looking at a some key design principles in visualisation, including a number of studies I hadn’t seen before but will definitely be including in my teaching in future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing and Scraping MyFitnessPal Data with Python</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2015/02/05/accessing-and-scraping-myfitnesspal-data-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 11:02:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2015/02/05/accessing-and-scraping-myfitnesspal-data-with-python/</guid>
      <description>Interesting news this morning that MyFitnessPal has been bought by Under Armour for $475 million. I&amp;rsquo;ve used MFP for many years now, and it was pretty helpful in helping me lose all the excess PhD weight that I&amp;rsquo;d put on, and then maintaining a healthy(ish) lifestyle since 2010.
News of an acquisition always has me slightly worried though - not for someone else having access to my data, as I&amp;rsquo;ve made my peace with the fact that using a free service generally means that it&amp;rsquo;s me that&amp;rsquo;s being sold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NHS Hackday 2015</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2015/01/26/nhs-hackday-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 10:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2015/01/26/nhs-hackday-2015/</guid>
      <description>This weekend I took part in an incredibly successful NHS hackday, hosted at Cardiff University and organised by Anne Marie Cunningham and James Morgan. We went as a team from the MSc in Computational Journalism, with myself and Glyn attending along with Pooja, Nikita, Annalisa and Charles. At the last-minute I recruited a couple of ringers as well, dragging along Rhys Priestland Dr William Wilberforce Webberley from Comsc and Dr Matthew Williams, previously of this parish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CompJ Labs - Postcodes</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2015/01/05/compj-labs-postcodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 09:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2015/01/05/compj-labs-postcodes/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve thrown up a post on compj.cs.cf.ac.uk about some work we&amp;rsquo;ve done looking at empty properties in Cardiff. I&amp;rsquo;ll add further posts over the coming weeks about other data analysis we&amp;rsquo;ve done on this topic, and new work looking at the Welsh Assembly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick and Dirty Twitter API in Python</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2014/11/19/quick-and-dirty-twitter-api-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 12:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2014/11/19/quick-and-dirty-twitter-api-in-python/</guid>
      <description>QUICK DISCLAIMER: this is a quick and dirty solution to a problem, so may not represent best coding practice, and has absolutely no error checking or handling. Use with caution&amp;hellip;
A recent project has needed me to scrape some data from Twitter. I considered using Tweepy, but as it was a project for the MSc in Computational Journalism, I thought it would be more interesting to write our own simple Twitter API wrapper in Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational Journalism - &#39;a Manifesto&#39;</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2014/10/03/computational-journalism-a-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 08:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2014/10/03/computational-journalism-a-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>While Glyn and I have been discussing the new MSc course between ourselves and with others, we have repeatedly come up with the same issues and themes, again and again. As a planning exercise earlier in the summer, we gathered some of these together into a &amp;lsquo;manifesto&amp;rsquo;.
The manifesto is online on our main &amp;lsquo;Computational Journalism&amp;rsquo; website with a bit of extra commentary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GeoJSON and topoJSON for UK boundaries</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2014/09/17/geojson-and-topojson-for-uk-boundaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 10:05:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2014/09/17/geojson-and-topojson-for-uk-boundaries/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just put an archive online containing GeoJSON and topoJSON for UK boundary data. It&amp;rsquo;s all stored on Github, with a viewer and download site hosted on Github pages.
   Browser for the UK topoJSON stored in the Github repository    The data is all created from shapefiles released by the Office of National Statistics, Ordnance Survey and National Records Scotland, all under the Open Government and OS OpenData licences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCGs and WPCs via the medium of OAs</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2014/09/15/ccgs-and-wpcs-via-the-medium-of-oas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 14:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2014/09/15/ccgs-and-wpcs-via-the-medium-of-oas/</guid>
      <description>As I was eating lunch this afternoon, I spotted a conversation between @JoeReddington and @MySociety whizz past in Tweetdeck. I traced the conversation back to the beginning and found this request for data:
I&amp;#39;m looking for a dataset that shows which UK constituencies are in which NHS trust areas. Anyone?
&amp;mdash; retired account (@retired10072015) September 14, 2014 
I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of playing with geographic data recently while preparing to release a site making it easier to get GeoJSON boundaries of various areas in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foursquare icon downloading (yet again)</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2014/08/01/foursquare-icon-downloading-yet-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 07:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2014/08/01/foursquare-icon-downloading-yet-again/</guid>
      <description>Previously I&amp;rsquo;vewritten about a little script to download all the category icons from Foursquare and to create many different coloured versions of them. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently had to do this again for a project, and found my previous script did not work with a recent API version. I&amp;rsquo;ve updated the script to fix it and put it up on github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Computational Journalism about to launch</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2014/04/15/msc-computational-journalism-about-to-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 15:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2014/04/15/msc-computational-journalism-about-to-launch/</guid>
      <description>For the last two years I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a project with some colleagues in the school of Journalism, Media and Cultural Studies (JOMEC) here at Cardiff University and it&amp;rsquo;s finally all coming together. This week we&amp;rsquo;ve been able to announce that (subject to some final internal paperwork wrangling) we&amp;rsquo;ll be launching an MSc in Computational Journalism this September. The story of how the course came about is fairly long, but starts simply with a tweet (unfortunately missing the context, but you get the drift):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python &#43; OAuth</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2013/10/25/python-oauth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2013 09:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2013/10/25/python-oauth/</guid>
      <description>As part of a current project I had the misfortune of having to to deal with a bunch of OAuth authenticated web services using a command line script in Python. Usually this isn&amp;rsquo;t really a problem as most decent client libraries for services such as Twitter or Foursquare can handle the authentication requests themselves, usually wrapping their own internal OAuth implementation. However, when it comes to web services that don&amp;rsquo;t have existing python client libraries, you have to do the implementation yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KSRI Services Summer School - Social Computing Theory and Hackathon</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2013/09/24/ksri-services-summer-school-social-computing-theory-and-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 11:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2013/09/24/ksri-services-summer-school-social-computing-theory-and-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>I was invited by Simon Caton to come to the KSRI Services Summer School, held at KIT in Germany, to help him run a workshop session on Social Computing. We decided to use the session as a crash course in retrieving and manipulating data from Social Media APIs - showing the students the basics, then running a mini &amp;lsquo;hackathon&amp;rsquo; for the students to gain some practical experience.
I think the session went really well, the students seemed to enjoy it and the feedback was very positive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SWN Festival 2013 plans – part 1: the data (2!)</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2013/08/18/swn-festival-2013-plans-part-1-the-data-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2013 11:36:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2013/08/18/swn-festival-2013-plans-part-1-the-data-2/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, I used python and BeautifulSoup to grab the list of artists appearing at SWN Festival 2013, and to scrape their associated soundcloud/twitter/facebook/youtube links (where available).
However, there are more places to find music online than just those listed on the festival site, and some of those extra sources include additional data that I want to collect, so now we need to search these other sources for the artists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SWN Festival 2013 plans -  part 1: the data</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2013/08/14/swn-festival-2013-plans-part-1-the-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 12:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2013/08/14/swn-festival-2013-plans-part-1-the-data/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned, I&amp;rsquo;m planning on doing a bit more development work this year connected to the SWN Festival. The first stage is to get hold of the data associated with the festival in an accessible and machine readable form so it can be used in other apps.
Unfortunately (but unsurprisingly), being a smallish local festival, there is no API for any of the data. So, getting a list of the bands and their info means we need to resort to web scraping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SWN Festival 2013 - plans</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2013/08/11/swn-festival-2013-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 17:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2013/08/11/swn-festival-2013-plans/</guid>
      <description>Last year I had a go at creating a couple of web apps based around the bands playing the SWN Festival here in Cardiff. I love SWN with all my heart, it&amp;rsquo;s a permanent fixture in my calendar and even if (when) I leave Cardiff it&amp;rsquo;ll be the one thing I come back for every year. It&amp;rsquo;s a great way to see and discover new bands, but sometimes the sheer volume of music on offer can be overwhelming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Project update</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2013/07/25/summer-project-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 13:23:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2013/07/25/summer-project-update/</guid>
      <description>We are storming along with summer projects now, and starting to see some really good results.
Liam Turner (who is starting a PhD in the school in October) has been working hard to create a mobile version of the 4SQPersonality app. His work is coming along really well, with a great mobile HTML version now up and running, a native android wrapper working, and an iOS wrapper on its way. With any luck we&amp;rsquo;ll have mobile apps for both major platforms ready to be released before the summer is over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Sauce Hackathon - Post Mortem</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2013/04/22/open-sauce-hackathon-post-mortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 10:51:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2013/04/22/open-sauce-hackathon-post-mortem/</guid>
      <description>This weekend saw the second &amp;lsquo;Open Sauce Hackathon&amp;rsquo; run by undergraduate students here in the school. Last years was pretty successful, and they improved upon it this year, pulling in many more sponsors and offering more prizes.
Unlike last year, when I turned up having already decided with Jon Quinn what we were doing, I went along this year with no real ideas. I had a desire to do something with a map, as I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure building stuff connected to maps is going to play a big part in work over the next couple of months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced LaTeX Course</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2013/03/15/advanced-latex-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 15:22:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2013/03/15/advanced-latex-course/</guid>
      <description>Here are the slides and source code for the UGC Advanced LaTeX course, 15th March 2013
Introduction (Beginners Recap, Graphics &amp;amp; Figures) - handouts and source BibTeX and Referencing - handouts &amp;amp; source Custom Commands &amp;amp; Environments, Source Code Listings, Tips &amp;amp; Tricks - handouts &amp;amp; source Exercise Sheets - handouts &amp;amp; source</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX notes and links</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2013/02/01/latex-notes-and-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 15:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2013/02/01/latex-notes-and-links/</guid>
      <description>During the `LaTeX for Beginners&amp;rsquo; UGC course on Friday 1st February I promised that I would upload the source code for my presentations along with some useful links:
 Introduction slides and source
 Maths slides and source
 Presentations slides and source
  Some useful links for people new to LaTeX:
 proTeXt and MacTeX distributions for Windows and Mac, respectively
 tex.stackexchange.com - community q&amp;amp;a site dedicated to LaTeX</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX beamer handouts (with frames and borders)</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2013/01/29/latex-beamer-handouts-with-frames-and-borders/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 09:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2013/01/29/latex-beamer-handouts-with-frames-and-borders/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m working on some notes for a beginners LaTeX course that I&amp;rsquo;m giving for the University Graduate College this week. In a temporary fit of insanity I decided it would be nice to write all the slides in LaTeX, so that I can distribute the source to the students so they get some real world LaTeX examples to go along with the course notes.
I was attempting to make handouts for the students using the great handoutWithNotes package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foursquare Personality Experiment</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2012/11/20/foursquare-personality-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 09:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2012/11/20/foursquare-personality-experiment/</guid>
      <description>Today we are finally starting to promote our latest experiment. It&amp;rsquo;s been online for about a month, but we haven&amp;rsquo;t told anyone about it while we&amp;rsquo;ve been finishing up the Year 2 deliverables for Recognition (the review is in a couple of weeks - fingers crossed!) Now however I can start publicly talking about it and encouraging people to take part and get involved!
We&amp;rsquo;re calling it the Foursquare Personality Experiment, and it&amp;rsquo;s available on the School of Computer Science &amp;amp; Informatics&amp;rsquo; website here:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SWN Artist Explorer</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2012/10/04/swn-artist-explorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 09:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2012/10/04/swn-artist-explorer/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of year again: SWN Festival is once more upon us. It&amp;rsquo;s the highlight of the musical year in Cardiff, and probably the one thing I&amp;rsquo;ll miss about the city when (if?) I leave. In fact, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty certain that even if I left the city I&amp;rsquo;d make the pilgrimage back once a year for SWN because it&amp;rsquo;s just too much fun to miss.
The lineup this year is another cracking one, but as usual with four days of bands spread across so many venues there are a whole bunch of names that I don&amp;rsquo;t recognise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django &#43; Last.FM Authentication</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2012/02/27/django-last.fm-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 09:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2012/02/27/django-last.fm-authentication/</guid>
      <description>Following a conversation with Jon last week, I&amp;rsquo;ve been having thoughts about playing around with Last.FM data again, having not looked at that API for a couple of years. We had discussed the possibility of using the Last.FM web services as part of a project at a hackathon that some of the undergraduates are running in a couple of weeks time, and since I&amp;rsquo;ve moved from primarily developing using Java to mainly using Python since I last did anything with Last.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foursquare Category Icon Downloader (2)</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2012/01/31/foursquare-category-icon-downloader-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 08:50:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2012/01/31/foursquare-category-icon-downloader-2/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE [01 August 2014]: Even more breaking! More recent version of the script here
Someone commented recently that the script I&amp;rsquo;d written to download the Foursquare category icons was broken. downloader.py is an update that works as of today (notice the URL param with today&amp;rsquo;s date) that will fetch all available sizes of all the category icons and store them in folders by size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BoxUK &#34;For the Social Good&#34; Hackday</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/11/22/boxuk-for-the-social-good-hackday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 10:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/11/22/boxuk-for-the-social-good-hackday/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I attended the &amp;ldquo;For the Social Good&amp;rdquo; hackday, organised by BoxUK and held at the Students Union at Cardiff University. As you may have gathered from the title, it was a hackday themed around creating apps that had some benefit to society. The event ran from 10am to 10pm, so it was a fairly short hack event compared to some, which had a big influence on what could be done during the time available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foursquare Hackathon Post Mortem</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/11/22/foursquare-hackathon-post-mortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 10:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/11/22/foursquare-hackathon-post-mortem/</guid>
      <description>Note: I wrote this post just after the hackathon, but then forgot to actually publish it! 
There&amp;rsquo;s a fair amount I learnt from taking part in and helping to organise the foursquare hackathon here at the university that probably deserves its own post. I&amp;rsquo;ll split it into two parts, the taking part and the organisation.
Organising a hack event There were a couple of things I learnt from helping to organise the event that perhaps weren&amp;rsquo;t clear to begin with:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colourful Foursquare category icons </title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/10/01/colourful-foursquare-category-icons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 16:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/10/01/colourful-foursquare-category-icons/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE [01 August 2014]: Even more breaking! More recent version of the script here
UPDATE 31/01/2011 - new version of the downloader script is here
A couple of projects I&amp;rsquo;m working on at the moment need the ability to add foursquare venues to a map. This is pretty straightforward, but what is also needed is the ability to distinguish between the categories of the venues. To do this, I&amp;rsquo;m adding custom markers to a google map at a venue location, with the marker having an icon representing the venue category.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foursquare Hackathon Cardiff - Day 2</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/09/19/foursquare-hackathon-cardiff-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 08:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/09/19/foursquare-hackathon-cardiff-day-2/</guid>
      <description>Wow. I thought Saturday was busy, but I was wrong. Saturday was a cake walk compared to the crazy nightmare that was Sunday. The challenge of trying to get something (anything) working before the app submission deadline was incredible. Coding was fast and intense, and required a lot of good communication and fast thinking. Unfortunately we hit a few roadblocks that slowed us down (2 hours debugging problems with django&amp;rsquo;s static file serving really didn&amp;rsquo;t help, neither did jQuery mobile being an absolute pain in the rear end), but by the end of the day we had a nice looking site with some actual working functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foursquare Hackathon Cardiff - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/09/17/foursquare-hackathon-cardiff-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 19:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/09/17/foursquare-hackathon-cardiff-day-1/</guid>
      <description>I was fully intending to try and live-blog the progress of the foursquare hackathon today, even going as far as to install a live blog plugin, but things have been going very quickly and we&amp;rsquo;ve been hitting the coding hard so I just haven&amp;rsquo;t had time!
We&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get a decent crowd in, a roughly 50:50 split of people we already knew from the School and other people from elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foursquare Hackathon</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/09/14/foursquare-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 15:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/09/14/foursquare-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>Along with Matthew Williams and Chris Gwilliams I&amp;rsquo;m helping to organise the Cardiff edition of the Foursquare global hackathon this weekend. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping it&amp;rsquo;ll be a pretty good event. Signup&amp;rsquo;s are looking pretty positive and I&amp;rsquo;m hopeful that we&amp;rsquo;ll get some decent apps being created.
The organising is actually quite fun, but it is remarkable how much there is to do and remember. Thankfully the School of Computer Science &amp;amp; Informatics are being very supportive and allowing us to host it there, which makes things easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Augmented Conversation</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/08/04/more-augmented-conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2011 09:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/08/04/more-augmented-conversation/</guid>
      <description>Another update on the summer project? Already? Yes.
The project is really cracking on. We&amp;rsquo;re two weeks from the end and beginning to see the results roll in, every meeting brings a new version of the software with more functionality. Nick has successfully written a nice framework that allows us to input conversations and automatically retrieve search results based on the topics of those conversations. Even the voice input works (almost) and we&amp;rsquo;ve got enough time to try and move on to some content extraction ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging in to websites with python</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/06/09/logging-in-to-websites-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 14:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/06/09/logging-in-to-websites-with-python/</guid>
      <description>As previously explained, I needed a python script to login to a website so I could access data. There&amp;rsquo;s loads of examples out on the web of how to do this, my solution (mashed together from many examples) is described below. For the whole script, jump to the end.
Firstly, we need to set some simple variables about the website we&amp;rsquo;re trying to log in to. Obviously, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to login to myfitnesspal, but this process should work with most websites that use a simple form + cookie based login process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping data from MyFitnessPal with python</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/06/09/scraping-data-from-myfitnesspal-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 08:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/06/09/scraping-data-from-myfitnesspal-with-python/</guid>
      <description>Following my success with extracting my Google Search History in a simple manner, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that I should do something similar to extract all the data I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeding into myfitnesspal for the last 5 months. As I briefly mentioned in the review of the app + website, the progress graphs leave a lot to be desired and there&amp;rsquo;s very little in the way of analysis of the data. I have a lot of questions about my progress and there is no easy way to answer all of them using just the website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Web History - Wordle</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/06/07/google-web-history-wordle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 08:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/06/07/google-web-history-wordle/</guid>
      <description>So, you&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded your Google search history, what&amp;rsquo;s the first thing you do? Split all the queries into individual words and make a wordle of course:
   A wordle of my Google search queries    There we have it - my use of Google for five years. Turns out I do programming and live in Cardiff. Who&amp;rsquo;d have thought it?
**edit: **why have I googled for google so much?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django &#43; Tweepy &#43; OAuth</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/04/04/django-tweepy-oauth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 18:27:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/04/04/django-tweepy-oauth/</guid>
      <description>There is a lot of information out there that talks about putting Django and Tweepy together to make a Twitter web app. I read a lot of it recently, and although a lot of it is helpful some of it can be quite complicated or out of date.
To make things simple, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d create an example Django project that just contains the basics needed to get up and running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Wordle</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/04/04/twitter-wordle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 13:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/04/04/twitter-wordle/</guid>
      <description>Next week we have the project partners coming over to Cardiff for a workshop. Stu and myself were discussing that we should have some way to display information throughout the day, something that makes it easy to pick out the main themes of talks etc. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the Wordle as a way of displaying text, so we thought it would be nice if we could have a dynamic Wordle displayed that people could add to throughout the workshop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fun with django...</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/03/28/fun-with-django.../</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 21:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/03/28/fun-with-django.../</guid>
      <description>One of the latest ideas we are working on for the new project is looking at how providing different amounts of information affects our perception of content. Even in pure implementation terms this is interestingly unlike any of the work I&amp;rsquo;ve done in the last few years, most of which was simulation based. &amp;ldquo;Code a simulation, run the simulation, analyse the results&amp;rdquo; has been a pattern of work since the beginning of my PhD and beyond.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>