<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching on Martin Chorley</title>
    <link>https://martinjc.com/tags/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teaching on Martin Chorley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 20:00:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://martinjc.com/tags/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes - 29th May 2017</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2017/06/04/weeknotes-29th-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 20:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2017/06/04/weeknotes-29th-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>Monday 29th May BANK HOLIDAY, innit
Tuesday 30th May OH GOD, NOW I&amp;rsquo;VE GOT A DAY LESS TO DO EVERYTHING!
Finished my visualisation coursework marking today. Generally really good quality across the board, and a really enjoyable set of work to mark. As time goes on, I&amp;rsquo;m liking this visualisation course more and more. It&amp;rsquo;s fun to teach as it&amp;rsquo;s an interesting and quite subjective field, which is not usual in a &amp;lsquo;normal&amp;rsquo; Computer Science course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes - 22nd May 2017</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2017/05/28/weeknotes-22nd-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 20:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2017/05/28/weeknotes-22nd-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>Strange week this week - coming back from holiday, lots of time spent catching up, arranging meetings and organising more meetings for next week
Monday 22.05.17 Most of Monday morning was spent dealing with all the emails I&amp;rsquo;d received while away last week. The usual mix of requests for information from admin, queries from current, potential and past students, and a number of things relating to projects that are either about to start or were supposed to have started by now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes - 14th May 2017</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2017/05/15/weeknotes-14th-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 20:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2017/05/15/weeknotes-14th-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>A very good week this week, in that I was only in work for 3 days, but still accomplished a lot. Through some convenient meetings I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get a whole mess of projects lined up for the next year or so, and I came out of the week on Friday very eager to get cracking on things.
Monday 8.5.17 This week started with our Assessment and Feedback focused teaching &amp;lsquo;away day&amp;rsquo;, which wasn&amp;rsquo;t really an away day because we didn&amp;rsquo;t go anywhere, but which was incredibly useful nonetheless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CompJ Labs - Postcodes</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2015/01/05/compj-labs-postcodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 09:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2015/01/05/compj-labs-postcodes/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve thrown up a post on compj.cs.cf.ac.uk about some work we&amp;rsquo;ve done looking at empty properties in Cardiff. I&amp;rsquo;ll add further posts over the coming weeks about other data analysis we&amp;rsquo;ve done on this topic, and new work looking at the Welsh Assembly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational Journalism - &#39;a Manifesto&#39;</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2014/10/03/computational-journalism-a-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 08:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2014/10/03/computational-journalism-a-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>While Glyn and I have been discussing the new MSc course between ourselves and with others, we have repeatedly come up with the same issues and themes, again and again. As a planning exercise earlier in the summer, we gathered some of these together into a &amp;lsquo;manifesto&amp;rsquo;.
The manifesto is online on our main &amp;lsquo;Computational Journalism&amp;rsquo; website with a bit of extra commentary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Graphical Web 2014</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2014/09/04/the-graphical-web-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 10:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2014/09/04/the-graphical-web-2014/</guid>
      <description>photo of the author outside Winchester cathedral    Last week I had a lovely time down in Winchester with m&amp;rsquo;colleague, attending The Graphical Web 2014. This year the theme was &amp;lsquo;Visual Storytelling&amp;rsquo;, so I&amp;rsquo;d gone along to see what new things we could learn about visualisation to include in the MSc in Computational Journalism. We&amp;rsquo;d also already had a few conversations about the course with people who were going to be at the conference, so we were planning to take the opportunity to chat in person about their involvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unified Diff and recruiting Guest Lecturers</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2014/07/23/unified-diff-and-recruiting-guest-lecturers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 11:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2014/07/23/unified-diff-and-recruiting-guest-lecturers/</guid>
      <description>Last week I gave a quick lightning talk at UnifiedDiff - a local tech meetup here in Cardiff. The main point of the talk was to try and recruit more industry involvement for our new MSc in Computational Journalism - preferably by getting some web developers and software engineers in to give guest lectures on the tools, languages and processes they use.
The talk went well, and I&amp;rsquo;ve had several offers from people wanting to get involved and add some real value to the course, which is brilliant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Computational Journalism about to launch</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2014/04/15/msc-computational-journalism-about-to-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 15:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2014/04/15/msc-computational-journalism-about-to-launch/</guid>
      <description>For the last two years I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a project with some colleagues in the school of Journalism, Media and Cultural Studies (JOMEC) here at Cardiff University and it&amp;rsquo;s finally all coming together. This week we&amp;rsquo;ve been able to announce that (subject to some final internal paperwork wrangling) we&amp;rsquo;ll be launching an MSc in Computational Journalism this September. The story of how the course came about is fairly long, but starts simply with a tweet (unfortunately missing the context, but you get the drift):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KSRI Services Summer School - Social Computing Theory and Hackathon</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2013/09/24/ksri-services-summer-school-social-computing-theory-and-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 11:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2013/09/24/ksri-services-summer-school-social-computing-theory-and-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>I was invited by Simon Caton to come to the KSRI Services Summer School, held at KIT in Germany, to help him run a workshop session on Social Computing. We decided to use the session as a crash course in retrieving and manipulating data from Social Media APIs - showing the students the basics, then running a mini &amp;lsquo;hackathon&amp;rsquo; for the students to gain some practical experience.
I think the session went really well, the students seemed to enjoy it and the feedback was very positive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Media Lecture Experiment</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2013/04/22/social-media-lecture-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 10:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2013/04/22/social-media-lecture-experiment/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve very recently had the opportunity to be involved in a different kind of lecture here at the School of Computer Science and Informatics. For his final year project one of our third year students (Samuel Boyes) is assessing the use of modern technology, social networking and video conferencing as part of the traditional lecture. As I had already been asked a few weeks ago to give a guest lecture in Matt Williams&amp;rsquo; module Fundamentals of Computing with Java, on the topic of code maintainability/readability, we were presented with a nice opportunity to test out Sam&amp;rsquo;s theories in an actual lecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced LaTeX Course</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2013/03/15/advanced-latex-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 15:22:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2013/03/15/advanced-latex-course/</guid>
      <description>Here are the slides and source code for the UGC Advanced LaTeX course, 15th March 2013
Introduction (Beginners Recap, Graphics &amp;amp; Figures) - handouts and source BibTeX and Referencing - handouts &amp;amp; source Custom Commands &amp;amp; Environments, Source Code Listings, Tips &amp;amp; Tricks - handouts &amp;amp; source Exercise Sheets - handouts &amp;amp; source</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX notes and links</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2013/02/01/latex-notes-and-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 15:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2013/02/01/latex-notes-and-links/</guid>
      <description>During the `LaTeX for Beginners&amp;rsquo; UGC course on Friday 1st February I promised that I would upload the source code for my presentations along with some useful links:
 Introduction slides and source
 Maths slides and source
 Presentations slides and source
  Some useful links for people new to LaTeX:
 proTeXt and MacTeX distributions for Windows and Mac, respectively
 tex.stackexchange.com - community q&amp;amp;a site dedicated to LaTeX</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>