<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conference on Martin Chorley</title>
    <link>/tags/conference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conference on Martin Chorley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 10:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Graphical Web 2014</title>
      <link>/2014/09/04/the-graphical-web-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 10:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/09/04/the-graphical-web-2014/</guid>
      <description>photo of the author outside Winchester cathedral    Last week I had a lovely time down in Winchester with m&amp;rsquo;colleague, attending The Graphical Web 2014. This year the theme was &amp;lsquo;Visual Storytelling&amp;rsquo;, so I&amp;rsquo;d gone along to see what new things we could learn about visualisation to include in the MSc in Computational Journalism. We&amp;rsquo;d also already had a few conversations about the course with people who were going to be at the conference, so we were planning to take the opportunity to chat in person about their involvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SCA 2013 - Visiting Patterns and Personality of Foursquare Users</title>
      <link>/2013/10/01/sca-2013-visiting-patterns-and-personality-of-foursquare-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 12:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/10/01/sca-2013-visiting-patterns-and-personality-of-foursquare-users/</guid>
      <description>Nice work by [@martinjc](https://twitter.com/martinjc) on Foursquare checkins and personality # sca2013 [pic.twitter.com/9afebFrzYS](http://t.co/9afebFrzYS) — Shaun Lawson (@shaunlawson) [October 1, 2013](https://twitter.com/shaunlawson/statuses/384979369175027712) Today was presentation day for me at SCA 2013 - I was presenting the initial results of the Foursquare experiment, which has now been running for a while. The presentation seemed to go really well - I think it&amp;rsquo;s the strongest work I&amp;rsquo;ve done yet, and so it was easy to talk well and with confidence about it, which led to a nice talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SocialCom 2012</title>
      <link>/2012/09/07/socialcom-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 13:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/07/socialcom-2012/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just returned from SocialCom 2012 and figured it was worth a post to round it all up. This is not that post however; that will take a little longer to write as there were quite a few really interesting and relevant talks to round up. I also had some good discussions about the work we&amp;rsquo;ve been doing, the work we&amp;rsquo;re planning to do and some of the work that others are doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WowMom 2011</title>
      <link>/2011/06/29/wowmom-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 09:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/06/29/wowmom-2011/</guid>
      <description>Last week I attended WowMom 2011 in Lucca, Italy. The conference was pretty good, but I was mainly there for the Autonomic and Opportunistic Computing (AOC) workshop where I was presenting some work, as I mentioned in an earlier post. The workshop was really interesting, a lot of the work was relevant to work we&amp;rsquo;d done in the past on the SocialNets project and work we&amp;rsquo;re doing in the future with the Recognition project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>