<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Movies on Martin Chorley</title>
    <link>https://martinjc.com/tags/movies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Movies on Martin Chorley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 10:37:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://martinjc.com/tags/movies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SciSCREEN - &#39;Her&#39;</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2014/03/19/sciscreen-her/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 10:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2014/03/19/sciscreen-her/</guid>
      <description>Last month I was invited along as a guest speaker for the regular sciSCREEN event held at Chapter Arts Centre. This is a great event that combines a showing of a movie with a discussion session about the themes and science issues presented in the film. A short essay based on my rambling improvised talk is below, and has been posted on the sciSCREEN website here.
&amp;lsquo;Her&amp;rsquo; and Artificial Intelligence &amp;lsquo;Her&amp;rsquo; presents us with a near-future world in which the way we interact with computers has moved on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-Processed Dinosaurs</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2013/08/28/post-processed-dinosaurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 10:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2013/08/28/post-processed-dinosaurs/</guid>
      <description>Finding myself with a free afternoon this week, I strolled down to the local Odeon to see Jurassic Park: IMAX 3D. (It should be noted that the &amp;lsquo;IMAX&amp;rdquo; bit doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean much - the screen at the Odeon is nowhere near as big as a true &amp;lsquo;IMAX&amp;rsquo; screen). I should say, I love this film a lot - hence my willingness to pay £12 (£12!!??!) to see it again on the big screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cinema 2012 - the review</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2013/02/06/cinema-2012-the-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 14:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2013/02/06/cinema-2012-the-review/</guid>
      <description>At the beginning of the year I embarked upon a challenge: watch 100 movies in the cinema in 1 year. I thought it would be fun, but difficult.
It was fun.
It was difficult.
This is a not very brief account of that year, starting with the best movies that were released this year and that I saw in the cinema. In no particular order, I think the best movies released this year that I saw in the cinema were:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Movies in the Cinema in 1 Year</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2012/03/04/100-movies-in-the-cinema-in-1-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2012 22:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2012/03/04/100-movies-in-the-cinema-in-1-year/</guid>
      <description>After reading this blog post at the end of January I decided that watching at least 100 movies in the cinema in a year was the kind of challenge I could get behind. Last year&amp;rsquo;s challenge to get fit and healthy was fairly successful and seemed like much harder work than going to the cinema a few times could ever be. After all, 100 movies a year is less than 2 a week, so it must be easy, right?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>