<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wordle on Martin Chorley</title>
    <link>/tags/wordle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wordle on Martin Chorley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 08:04:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/wordle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>not another bloody wordle?!?!</title>
      <link>/2013/08/20/not-another-bloody-wordle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 08:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/20/not-another-bloody-wordle/</guid>
      <description>(UPDATE: an earlier version of this was totally wrong. It&amp;rsquo;s better now.)
Inspired by a Facebook post from a colleague, I decided to waste ten minutes this week knocking together a word cloud from the text of my thesis. The process was pretty straightforward.
First up - extracting the text from the thesis. Like all good scienticians, my thesis was written in LaTeX. I thought I could have used a couple of different tools to extract the plain text from the raw .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Web History - Wordle</title>
      <link>/2011/06/07/google-web-history-wordle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 08:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/06/07/google-web-history-wordle/</guid>
      <description>So, you&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded your Google search history, what&amp;rsquo;s the first thing you do? Split all the queries into individual words and make a wordle of course:
   A wordle of my Google search queries    There we have it - my use of Google for five years. Turns out I do programming and live in Cardiff. Who&amp;rsquo;d have thought it?
**edit: **why have I googled for google so much?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Wordle</title>
      <link>/2011/04/04/twitter-wordle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 13:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/04/04/twitter-wordle/</guid>
      <description>Next week we have the project partners coming over to Cardiff for a workshop. Stu and myself were discussing that we should have some way to display information throughout the day, something that makes it easy to pick out the main themes of talks etc. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the Wordle as a way of displaying text, so we thought it would be nice if we could have a dynamic Wordle displayed that people could add to throughout the workshop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>