<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Weeknotes on Martin Chorley</title>
    <link>/tags/weeknotes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Weeknotes on Martin Chorley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 20:00:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/weeknotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes - 29th May 2017</title>
      <link>/2017/06/04/weeknotes-29th-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 20:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/04/weeknotes-29th-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>Monday 29th May BANK HOLIDAY, innit
Tuesday 30th May OH GOD, NOW I&amp;rsquo;VE GOT A DAY LESS TO DO EVERYTHING!
Finished my visualisation coursework marking today. Generally really good quality across the board, and a really enjoyable set of work to mark. As time goes on, I&amp;rsquo;m liking this visualisation course more and more. It&amp;rsquo;s fun to teach as it&amp;rsquo;s an interesting and quite subjective field, which is not usual in a &amp;lsquo;normal&amp;rsquo; Computer Science course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes - 22nd May 2017</title>
      <link>/2017/05/28/weeknotes-22nd-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 20:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/28/weeknotes-22nd-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>Strange week this week - coming back from holiday, lots of time spent catching up, arranging meetings and organising more meetings for next week
Monday 22.05.17 Most of Monday morning was spent dealing with all the emails I&amp;rsquo;d received while away last week. The usual mix of requests for information from admin, queries from current, potential and past students, and a number of things relating to projects that are either about to start or were supposed to have started by now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeknotes - 14th May 2017</title>
      <link>/2017/05/15/weeknotes-14th-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 20:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/15/weeknotes-14th-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>A very good week this week, in that I was only in work for 3 days, but still accomplished a lot. Through some convenient meetings I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get a whole mess of projects lined up for the next year or so, and I came out of the week on Friday very eager to get cracking on things.
Monday 8.5.17 This week started with our Assessment and Feedback focused teaching &amp;lsquo;away day&amp;rsquo;, which wasn&amp;rsquo;t really an away day because we didn&amp;rsquo;t go anywhere, but which was incredibly useful nonetheless.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>