<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Martin Chorley</title>
    <link>https://martinjc.com/tags/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Martin Chorley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 19:12:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://martinjc.com/tags/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>sitting on the dock of the bay</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2014/09/08/sitting-on-the-dock-of-the-bay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 19:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2014/09/08/sitting-on-the-dock-of-the-bay/</guid>
      <description>While we negotiate the transition from the old house which we&amp;rsquo;ve sold to the new house we&amp;rsquo;ve just bought we&amp;rsquo;ve been renting a lovely flat up on Penarth head. One of the main benefits of this flat is the glorious view over Cardiff Bay and to the city centre beyond. No matter what time it is, whenever I pass by the living room window I end up staring out across the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edinburgh Festival... Day One (The Shows)</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/08/25/edinburgh-festival...-day-one-the-shows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 20:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/08/25/edinburgh-festival...-day-one-the-shows/</guid>
      <description>Our first show was Dave Gorman at Assembly at the George Square Lecture Theatre, so after checking in we headed straight over there. We sat in the sun on the steps outside the venue and supped a couple of pints of Deuchars. We shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have bothered, it was served so cold you couldn&amp;rsquo;t taste anything, although maybe that was a blessing seeing as it came from a bar inside a shipping container and was served in a plastic cup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edinburgh 2011.... Day One (The Journey)</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2011/08/25/edinburgh-2011....-day-one-the-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 19:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2011/08/25/edinburgh-2011....-day-one-the-journey/</guid>
      <description>Despite having lived in Edinburgh for almost a year on and off while doing my MSc, I&amp;rsquo;ve never been up there at festival time. We decided to rectify this, so earlier on in the year (way earlier on in the year) we booked some accommodation for the second week of the festival and made our plans to hit the city for a festival holiday. Over a few posts I&amp;rsquo;ll describe in laborious detail what we did, what we saw, and what we (or I) thought of it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>