<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Twitter on Martin Chorley</title>
    <link>https://martinjc.com/tags/twitter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Twitter on Martin Chorley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 12:13:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://martinjc.com/tags/twitter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick and Dirty Twitter API in Python</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2014/11/19/quick-and-dirty-twitter-api-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 12:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2014/11/19/quick-and-dirty-twitter-api-in-python/</guid>
      <description>QUICK DISCLAIMER: this is a quick and dirty solution to a problem, so may not represent best coding practice, and has absolutely no error checking or handling. Use with caution&amp;hellip;
A recent project has needed me to scrape some data from Twitter. I considered using Tweepy, but as it was a project for the MSc in Computational Journalism, I thought it would be more interesting to write our own simple Twitter API wrapper in Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do people decide whether or not to read a tweet? </title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2014/11/04/how-do-people-decide-whether-or-not-to-read-a-tweet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 12:31:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2014/11/04/how-do-people-decide-whether-or-not-to-read-a-tweet/</guid>
      <description>It turns out that an existing relationship with the author of the tweet is one of the main factors influencing how someone decides whether or not to read a tweet. At the same time, a large number associated with a tweet can also make the tweet more attractive to readers.
Our latest Open Access research has discovered how much effect the information about a tweet has on whether people decide to read it or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KSRI Services Summer School - Social Computing Theory and Hackathon</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2013/09/24/ksri-services-summer-school-social-computing-theory-and-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 11:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2013/09/24/ksri-services-summer-school-social-computing-theory-and-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>I was invited by Simon Caton to come to the KSRI Services Summer School, held at KIT in Germany, to help him run a workshop session on Social Computing. We decided to use the session as a crash course in retrieving and manipulating data from Social Media APIs - showing the students the basics, then running a mini &amp;lsquo;hackathon&amp;rsquo; for the students to gain some practical experience.
I think the session went really well, the students seemed to enjoy it and the feedback was very positive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Projects</title>
      <link>https://martinjc.com/2012/06/26/summer-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 11:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinjc.com/2012/06/26/summer-projects/</guid>
      <description>Both of the summer projects that I&amp;rsquo;m supervising with Walter Colombo have now started, with two students joining us for 8 weeks over summer to gain some experience of the research environment and work on some (hopefully) interesting projects.
One of our students (James) is investigating the ranking of content on Twitter by pairwise comparison. He&amp;rsquo;s currently building a website to allow comparison of tweets and hopefully we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to get enough people to have a go at it that we can gather a large number of ratings of tweets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>