<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Martin Chorley</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Martin Chorley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 11:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic Parent</title>
      <link>/2017/11/29/academic-parent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/29/academic-parent/</guid>
      <description>I, like many others, made note of a recent tweet by Nathan Hall discussing the attitude of his colleagues when he prioritises family over career:
I still find it interesting the puzzled expressions I get from colleagues when mentioning how childcare impacts my academic work; when explaining why I try to minimize conference travel, leave the office by 4 PM, or sometimes cancel meetings due to dad responsibilities.
&amp;mdash; Nathan C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataJConf Debrief</title>
      <link>/2017/08/05/datajconf-debrief/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/05/datajconf-debrief/</guid>
      <description>DataJConf at UCD    A month ago we held the first European Data and Computational Journalism Conference in Dublin, Ireland. This is a long overdue post about that event.
The conference idea started as all good ideas do, in the pub and with a tweet. It was at a social event during ICWSM &amp;lsquo;16 where I was first introduced to Bahareh Heravi, a data journalism lecturer from UCD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-Graduation Thoughts</title>
      <link>/2017/08/04/post-graduation-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 14:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/04/post-graduation-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Last month I took part in my first graduation ceremony as part of the academic procession. This is the bit where staff members from the school(s) that are graduating get dressed up in their silly robes, &amp;lsquo;process&amp;rsquo; into the graduation ceremony, and sit on stage for an hour or so clapping as all their students stride across the stage to shake the VC&amp;rsquo;s hand and graduate from their degree.
It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fun, because who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like dressing up in silly robes and a hat?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>