<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Phd on Martin Chorley</title>
    <link>/tags/phd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Phd on Martin Chorley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 08:04:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/phd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>not another bloody wordle?!?!</title>
      <link>/2013/08/20/not-another-bloody-wordle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 08:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/20/not-another-bloody-wordle/</guid>
      <description>(UPDATE: an earlier version of this was totally wrong. It&amp;rsquo;s better now.)
Inspired by a Facebook post from a colleague, I decided to waste ten minutes this week knocking together a word cloud from the text of my thesis. The process was pretty straightforward.
First up - extracting the text from the thesis. Like all good scienticians, my thesis was written in LaTeX. I thought I could have used a couple of different tools to extract the plain text from the raw .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD Post-mortem - The Summary</title>
      <link>/2012/11/16/phd-post-mortem-the-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 11:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/11/16/phd-post-mortem-the-summary/</guid>
      <description>I originally wrote a whole bunch of posts (6!) about my PhD, what went wrong, how I felt about it, and so on. Then I read it all back and it was a bunch of hugely self-indulgent poorly written bollocks (what&amp;rsquo;s new?), so I decided not to publish it. Maybe sometime later I&amp;rsquo;ll get round to it, but for now, the tl-dr; is:
My viva was a car crash, my examiners hated my work, I got too depressed over the result to engage with the corrections process, had another viva, it was terrible but not as bad, I pulled it together and corrected it all in the end, thanks to some excellent support from everyone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 years, 1 month and 4 days later...</title>
      <link>/2012/11/05/7-years-1-month-and-4-days-later.../</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 11:44:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/11/05/7-years-1-month-and-4-days-later.../</guid>
      <description>This is a post I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting to write for a very long time. A very, very, long time. As I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting so long I&amp;rsquo;m going to start with the good news: on the 30th October 2012 I finally received confirmation that my examiners had accepted my PhD corrections and I should be approved for my degree. I&amp;rsquo;m Dr Martin Chorley.
Exactly how long I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting to write this depends on your point of view.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>