<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshop on Martin Chorley</title>
    <link>/tags/workshop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workshop on Martin Chorley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 20:17:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/workshop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Atom Plugins for Web Development</title>
      <link>/2016/10/05/atom-plugins-for-web-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 20:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/05/atom-plugins-for-web-development/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had a number of students in my web-dev module asking me what plugins I’m using in my text editor, so I thought I’d dash off a quick blog post on the plugins I find useful day-to-day. (Actually, most people are normally asking me ‘how did you do that thing where you typed one word and suddenly you had a whole HTML page? The answer is I used a plugin, so ‘what plugins do you use?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Software Institute – Research Data Visualisation Workshop</title>
      <link>/2016/08/01/sustainable-software-institute-research-data-visualisation-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 20:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/08/01/sustainable-software-institute-research-data-visualisation-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Last week I gave a talk and delivered a hands on session at the Sustainable Software Institute’s ‘Research Data Visualisation Workshop‘ which was held at Manchester University. It was a really engaging event, with a lot of good discussion on the issues surrounding data visualisation.
Professor Jessie Kennedy from Edinburgh Napier University gave a great keynote looking at a some key design principles in visualisation, including a number of studies I hadn’t seen before but will definitely be including in my teaching in future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSAR Workshop</title>
      <link>/2013/10/01/csar-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 10:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/10/01/csar-workshop/</guid>
      <description>This week, as part of the &amp;ldquo;Third International Conference on Social Computing and its Applications&amp;rdquo; we held a workshop &amp;ldquo;Collective Social Awareness and Relevance (CSAR)&amp;rdquo;. Organising the workshop (along with Walter Colombo) over the last couple of months has been an interesting process - this is the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve had the chance to get involved in &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; workshop organisation, so this is the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve seen the process up close.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>